e
[Music]
how
a
[Music]
w
oh
[Music]
o
w
[Music]
welcome Mana church family so good to
have you here with us today for church
and to worship get together with to
worship God together on the Sabbath
we're just happy that you are here with
us today please there's a lot of you in
the chat and online so please put in the
chat where you're viewing from we want
to say a special welcome to you um just
having you here with us to worship on
this uh Sabbath day we know this is a
hectic time of year because every every
body's either traveling or uh for
Christmas to visit family and all of
these type of things but we are just
happy that you took some time away from
all the hustle and bustle work school
even Christmas things to just be here to
worship God together on the Sabbath so
just want to welcome uh everyone again
that's here and that's viewing from all
around the world Amen um we have a
special uh I think uh uh service today
yes always always and we again just want
to welcome uh each one of you for those
of you that are visiting for the first
time we want to make sure that uh that
our
regular uh guests and members invite or
welcome you yes and uh we put a one in
the chat if you're visiting for the
first time and we look forward to
worshiping with with uh all of you today
yes all right so we have lots of people
commenting all right well we have yes
yes we have I don't want to mispronounce
your name but you are visiting from
England want to welcome you here and
specifically what part oh Cambridge
Cambridge uh so we want to welcome you
all the way across the pond welcome to
living Mana Church good to have you here
uh with us today and as you guys are
still putting in the chat where you're
viewing from uh we just want to again
welcome everyone and I see our people in
the chat there are putting uh they're
welcome you as well so we're just all
welcoming each other to church today
again this is the time of
year where everybody's talking about
Jesus or at least baby Jesus and they're
just they're just thinking of God even
if even if they don't believe in God
it's kind of hard to miss God this time
of year yeah to hear about God because
it's it's everywhere and so um we of
course we here are always talking about
God and his love and the birth of Jesus
and what that means to us as Christians
but the world is talking about that at
least once uh once a year at least
everybody is talking about it or
surrounded by it because there's
Christmas uh things all around and so um
this is just the time of year that we
really just want to focus on what
Jesus's uh birth meant and then
ultimately his sacrifice that he made
for us yeah the reason that he came into
this world reason why he came and of
course you know nobody knows the date
that he was born right we sure don't so
there's a lot of oh this isn't really
you know we don't know if he was born on
December 25th well we know he wasn't
born on December 25th but right uh I
think that the fact that people are uh
are taking this time to talk about Jesus
is definitely a right an excellent
opportunity to to share so it gives you
um it gives you an opportunity to be
able to share it's an open it's a it's a
huge opening uh to be able to share the
gospel to some that maybe at other times
in the year when you know they're not
thinking about Jesus or God you know it
might be a little bit more challenging
but this time of year you have an
opening and so definitely T definitely
take advantage of that um we are uh just
excited we have actually uh living Mana
church has a Christmas um party tomorrow
online obviously online um on we're
going to hear more about that in the in
the um Divine worship I will give you
more information about that but if you
can please fit it into your schedule the
good thing about living matter church is
we are with you even if you're on the
road like we you you could be somewhere
and you you can grab your phone and you
can still attend our virtual Christmas
party or you know if you're on your
computer somewhere it's like you can
definitely be there so looking forward
to that I know I'm sharing something and
you're sharing uh something as well
that's right
and there's other great things that are
going to be um a part of it I I am
getting there I people are saying what
does your shirt say we're about to tell
you about to tell you that okay so so
the search says God is
still writing your story stop trying
to steal the
pen God is still writing your story stop
trying to steal the pen and I just you
know I was just thinking I was like well
do I have a message that will kind of go
in with Christmas I mean I don't know
but this message definitely uh just
stood out to me um because there's so
many times that we we say oh we want God
to do this this and that in our lives
but we still try to make things happen
on our own and try to take charge
instead of trusting him we try to take
the pen and write the story where God is
the author of our story and he's going
to write so we can just sit back and
relax you know how they tell you when
you're flying on a plane just sit back
and relax and you know as we enjoy the
ride enjoy the ride enjoy the ride enjoy
the ride of life and let God Write Your
Story don't try to take charge of that I
know for me and I'm a planner and my
planning a lot of times turns
into anxiety and control because I'm
trying to take the pen and no God is
like sit back and enjoy the ride and
you'll be happier and you'll be more
peaceful so amen that is what today's
shirt says and I do want to just send a
quick shout out to the Godfree family I
know I thought I saw David Godfrey on
there and then I saw somebody welcoming
him welcome guys it was good to see you
just a few weeks ago I thought that's
what I I don't know if it's just is here
and I don't know if who who else is on
but uh I think it's the god of them
family welcome we love and appreciate
you guys have always loved and
appreciate you guys for so many years so
it's good to have you guys on here yes
all right well looks like not a lot of
you told me where you're viewing from so
you just get a special
welcome but you're chatting you're
chatting in the chat so uh you get a
second you get a second opportunity when
we go into Divine worship um just as got
to do this got to always talk about the
convocation the convocation is coming up
um you're getting no you know getting
information you can go to the website
you're going to get more information in
the Divine worship but I always want to
remind you guys that it's coming May 1st
through 4th we are excited you will get
more details about the program and
things that we're doing um at in the
beginning of of the new year so we are
but again we are excited to meet so many
of you and so many people are are
reaching out saying they're planning on
coming they're getting things all
together so that they'll be able to do
that some are we have international
people that are that live
internationally and um they're members
or they're their family a part of living
Mana church and they're coming so we're
looking uh forward to that and we are
excited to meet each and every one of
you so all right and there's the link in
the chat so if you want to just peruse
that uh you can do that um even now so
get your planning
started so we have a special yes we have
a special Sabbath School um exciting
while you introduce it yeah
so um several months ago I think we
started talking about the Plan of
Salvation uh revealed in the books of
the Bible yes um in chronological order
and um we started off with the Book of
Ezekiel and that was
like people say the bomb.com that was
the bomb that was that was that was
amazing that was awesome absolutely um
we were able to track like the theme of
The Great controversy by looking at the
segments of the Book of Ezekiel and
seeing that uh in the way that it is
written the chronological order of the
book uh lays out the Plan of Salvation
from the birth of Christ all the way to
the second coming right so actually all
the way to the close of the Millennium
and a lot of people were like how is
that even possible we went through it
and everyone was like wow this is
absolutely amazing so uh then blown away
yeah we did we followed up with a second
book um and we started going through a a
a a series I think we only did two we
may have done three I I think it was two
it was uh first and second Samuel I
think so and I thought you couldn't do
it in a day yeah in in one setting y but
you did yeah so we're going to continue
that today because we said we're going
to do you know do some more books and
today we are going to hit first and
second Kings first and second Kings and
um we're going to trace the great
controversy through these two books now
um as I was uh putting together this
study this morning and I actually used
uh used a a special uh software to help
me actually re reformat this study okay
and It produced so much I was almost
like man this might be this could very
easily be like
a seven or eight part series okay so
we're not going to complete first and
second Kings today which is fine yeah
okay I mean there's so much to study in
each segment in each part um but I still
don't want people to lose the chronology
cuz we can get caught caught up so much
in the details that we lose the the the
idea of hey this is the chronology
so um in this study which we're going to
pray and then we're going to walk
through this study on the screen but
there's so much in this study that I I
will put these uh these slides up on the
screen but we're not going to go through
everything on the screen we're just
going to kind of use it as a marker okay
um but if you want to download this it
will be available to you you can
actually do this study on your own you
can do this study with a group you can
do it in a small group
um there questions that are in the study
you know study this uh uh discussions
things of that nature so uh it it really
is a very powerful study but we're going
to see how far we get okay and um and so
I think it's a perfect time to ask you
to invite your friends and family to
church today because we're about to
start a very powerful I know it's going
to be powerful study so click share and
again if you're and if you have not
likeed
um if you're on living Mana YouTube
Channel please like and um subscribe and
share on your social media yeah okay all
right so uh let's begin T would you pray
for us yeah Heavenly Father Lord I just
want to thank you for this time together
um with our church family and and
viewing audience to study the Bible
together Lord we just invite your Holy
Spirit to to be with us here as we study
and see these amazing things that you
have put in your word and Lord I pray
that this will impact our lives in a
powerful way in Jesus name amen amen
amen all right so uh let's go to the
screen and once again we are looking at
the books of first and second Kings
first and 2 Kings and the first thing
that we're going to do remember we're
going to divide this book up so we're
going to just kind of touch on the the
overarching theme of portions of the
book in chronological order so we're
going to we're going to separate the
chapters are we're going to kind of
group the chapters together and the
first group that we're looking at is
chapters 1 through3 so First Kings
chapters 1 through3 and we're going to
see that basically what happens here is
there is an attempted
usurpation of the
throne okay
um to the point that David so the
characters in the story are David
Solomon and
adonijah and uh what we find here is
adonijah attempts to
seize the
throne
um the throne rightfully
belongs to
Solomon and David Solomon's
father basically makes a public
declaration that Solomon is the rightful
Heir
so what what we have here in the first
three chapters of uh First Kings is this
picture
of David
the father of
Solomon and
then adon's desire to take what belongs
to
Solomon he wants to usurp the throne
that belongs to Solomon and then the
father calls a
public uh
Gathering to
declare that the son is the rightful
King so that's chapters 1 through three
and what we're going to do is we're just
going to pause and ask the question okay
what event in salvational
history would this parallel what event
in salvational history would this
parallel what are you thinking of and
you know I haven't shared any of this
with you so I don't know if you have any
thoughts yet but just think okay we're
looking for parallel of uh of um Satan
in heaven uh trying to take over do what
did you just say Satan in heaven Lucifer
in heaven trying to take over God's
throne in heaven trying to take the
Throne of God God
um yeah
Wendy absolutely amazing this is
absolutely amazing like right there in
the first three chapters
it's almost as if this story of adonijah
and Solomon and David David is the
father Solomon is the rightful
son
adonijah the son of David as well but he
wants he wants the throne
right he wants the
throne M put a one in the chat if you're
already
seeing the parallel in essence where we
are beginning our story
mhm war in heaven so we now
know that the parallel will
begin with the Rebellion that took place
in heaven um let's let's go back to the
screen and I want you to note um note
the
parallel so
there we go so Harmony this is by the
way this is from uh let's see let me
scroll down a little bit this is from
eternity um from eternity
past uh which is a
compilation and I want you to know what
it
says regarding this war in heaven now
the perfect harmony of heaven was broken
the king of the universe summoned the
Heavenly Host before him that in their
presence might set forth the the true
position of his son and you'll see there
the parallels Heaven's initial state of
unity and peace the breaking down of
heavenly Harmony the king of the
universe calls a Heavenly Host God sets
forth the position of his true son this
is exactly what is going
on in this story of adonijah Solomon and
David and in fact uh I'mma go let me go
back to the screen very quickly and I
want to continue reading this is in
Patriarchs and Prophets page 38 she says
there had been no change let me go back
let me go back I think let me see
something real quick
here
okay so she says here there had been no
change in the position or authority of
Christ Lucifer's envy and
misrepresentation and his claims to
equality with Christ had made
necessary a statement of the true
position of the Son of God but this had
been but this had been the same from the
beginning many of the Angels however
were blinded by Lucifer's deception so
what we need to see here is that there's
no change in Christ it wasn't as if
Christ wasn't the rightful King before
but then suddenly at a period of time
the father was like okay um now Christ
is the rightful King this was done
simply
to make a public declaration in the face
of an uprising in
heaven the position of
Jesus and so this parallel really
becomes it's an amazing parallel it's
like in this story what what God is
doing is he's giving us a snapshot into
what happened in heaven right and when
we begin to understand that the Bible is
full of these kinds of snapshots
right where as we're looking at these
stories God has given us insight into
the great controversy into the Plan of
Salvation into events that happened in
heaven past yeah Michelle Hebrews 1 is a
good parallel to this right let all the
angels of God worship him um speaking
about the son so so so far and that's a
whole study in itself as you can see we
could spend this whole segment this
whole Sabbath School just talking about
this Rebellion what Lucifer attempted to
do in heaven right in usurping the
throne and the
father uh
uh making clear the position of who
Jesus
was but we're not going to do that you
can do that in this study when you
download this study guide you could do
that but we're not going to do that in
this in this Sabbath school right now
we're going to go on to the next section
right okay so let's go uh let's go back
to the
screen we're going to go back to the
screen and of course you can see there
uh uh some more you know just commentary
on this particular section uh and let me
read the reflection these opening
chapters in First Kings forhad of the
great controversy scene they highlight
the universal truth that only the
rightful King uh whether Solomon or
Christ has the authority to Reign the
conflict over kingship on Earth mirrors
the cosmic conflict in heaven where
Christ's divine right and position were
challenged by Lucifer so that's a nice
kind of summation of this parallel right
between these first three chapters now
let's go on to Chapters 4 4 to8 that's
our next segment chapters 4 to chapters
8 and what do chapters 4 to chapters 8
describe well here we have Solomon
Begins the work of building the Temple
on behalf of the father on behalf of his
father remember it was behalf on David
David said God told me Solomon was going
to build this Temple right there's a
whole another study on that which we're
not going to get into now
but from chapters 4 to chapter8 Solomon
is building the Temple so let's look at
some of these Solomon Begins the
Monumental task of constructing the
temple in Jerusalem a project his father
David had long desired to undertake the
building of the temple is described in
detail in 1 Kings 5-7 showcasing the
Grandeur and and intricacy of the Sacred
structure upon completing Solomon
dedicates the temple in a solemn and
joyous ceremony and the climax of the
dedication occurs when God's presence
fills the temple so that's kind of the
summation of chapters 4 to8 what is the
parallel if we're looking at events in
chronological
order what would what would what would
this next section signify what do you
all think and I I'mma look out for your
comments in the
chat but what do you think would be the
next
uh the next chapter if you will in the
great controversy so so the first is
occurring where there's rebellion in
heaven and now the Rebellion is over and
now the sun Begins the work of building
the Temple on behalf of the father
and people are commenting there so
people are starting comment say creation
too okay I mean we could go we can go
with that I mean that creation is is
pretty broad it is Broad but I mean if
you want to go into like literal like
like let's go literal literal literal
let's go well let's see how literal
you're talking well I just feel like
that's kind of fast forwarding if I go
to the literal
Temple that is real
built so I'm saying that's what I'm no
I'm saying the in the wilderness that
Temple I don't want to go that that's
too fast forward so that's why I'm
saying start wanting to start at
creation or or at least after the fall I
all right so and and someone's got the
answer in the chat but let's look at it
this way okay does Jesus begin his
ministry yeah okay there you go yeah uh
but
that's
uh Jennifer his ministry and like this
is a question actually we could
technically say his ministry starts
before the fall or after the fall starts
after the fall like after they sin yeah
so that's what I mean like you could
start that next phase would be when Adam
and Eve s yeah I mean you could start
you could start it from creation oh
Jesus created the world Etc but very
specifically we're talking about Jesus's
work of building the Temple Jesus came
into this world to
build a temple for his
father so what that Temple I have
questions about that I mean I get that
that makes sense no goad but
like I'm thinking well okay so if if I
mean okay so he came to build okay a
temple on this Earth for his father but
Satan was cast to earth right I mean he
was cast to Earth so um I don't know I
just see the ministry starting like
after after they fall not like him
creating is not a the Earth is not
create starting to create a temple I
guess I never looked at it quite like
that yeah so the focus is on the temple
okay right so it's not well when does
Solomon begin you know I was think of
the work that has to be done in a temple
so I guess I correlate that with sin so
the fall had to happen I'm over maybe
I'm overthinking it but it fits you know
the reason Jesus is coming to build the
temple is because of sin it's because of
the Fall MH but but um yeah Kendra very
good uh fill the temple or people with
God's spirit so remember Solomon comes
to build a temple in fact let's go back
to the
screen um and we're going to see the
parallel here Solomon's Temple the
physical temple built by Solomon was a
magnificent structure serving as a
center of worship of the Israelites it
presented God's Dwelling Place among the
people Jesus drew a parallel between
himself and the temple in John 2:19 he
said destroy this Temple and I and in
three days I will raise it up right this
statement foreshadows his death
Resurrection revealing that he's the
ultimate dwelling place for God and now
look at Ephesians chapter 2: 19
Ephesians chapter 2: 19 expands on this
concept describing Believers as being
built together in Christ right so Christ
comes to this world with a mission to
build a temple for his father what is
the temple we are the temple we are okay
so remember what happens on the day of
Pentecost like that right when Jesus
forms the church when he let's say this
way when he when he establishes the
church which is the temple the spirit of
God on the day of Pentecost falls from
heaven yes and
fills the temple temple which
is which is his church church we are the
temple yes Adena so watch now so far
we've gone from First Kings chapter 1 to
First Kings chapter 8 roughly chapter
nine and what we see is that in those
nine chapters you have a foreshadow I
shouldn't say a foreshadow you have a
I'm just going to call that a shadow not
a foreshadow is in something in the
future but a shadow of events that
happened in the past that's yeah right
something that's tracking with that's
right the so you got the fall of Heaven
from Lucifer in which he attempted to
usurp the throne
uh uh of Jesus and then you have Jesus
come into this world to build a temple
he completes the temple and the presence
of God on the day of Pentecost fills the
temple we are the temple the church is
the temple okay okay so let's go back to
the screen and um we're going to
go we're going to go to the next slide
and you know more commentary on literal
temples and spirit again you can
download this uh this um uh these slides
we'll share the link for that and um you
can go through this study in more detail
on your own but let's move to the next
section and I believe this is uh Second
Kings
chapter n 2 Kings chapter
n so the temple is finished and the
Covenant is
established and Solomon's Fame grows so
after the completion of The Magnificent
Temple a pivotal moment unfolds in the
reign of Solomon and the history of
Israel Solomon finishes building the
Temple uh building the grand Temple in
Jerusalem marking a significant
milestone in Israel's history God
Appears to Solomon and reaffirms the
Covenant as recorded in First Kings 9:
1-9 Solomon's Renown is increased
bringing honor and recognition to Israel
among the Nations so what I mean this is
this ought to be super simple if we're
paralleling so
far what is this what is the parallel
that we're looking at here so what's
happening with this
chapter
thoughts Covenant
established Fame
grows Solomon's name is now going out
like people know who he
is that's what I was going to say what
going to sayr what Christina said what
she said right yes upon the death burial
and resurrection of
Christ The Covenant is
sealed and this is where Jesus's Fame is
about to go into all the world right no
longer just Israel right but now it's
going into the whole world right okay
very simple parallel uh let's go back to
the screen
and what we'll see
here
um after the completion of the of the
Magnificent Temple oh I think we just
read that um so the parallel is Christ
finished work finished work right the
cealing of the New Testament the spread
of Christianity through the apostles and
and and the early church all of this
parallels Solomon's Fame put a five in
the chat if yall are following so far um
and and here's a whole study on you know
it is finished the the the the Covenant
renewal the completion of the temple the
global impact of of the work of Jesus
the work Jesus finished at the cross all
kind of reflection and questions you
could follow on anyway we're going to
move on in genes I'm sorry in second
Kings chapter
10 the Gentiles are now coming to
Solomon and this is where the story of
Sheba you know Sheba comes to Solomon
asking for his wisdom like you know or
inquiring about his wisdom and and his
knowledge and all and and all these
things so again it's a very simple
parallel
right the Gentiles are coming to Solomon
right yeah not only does his Fame go out
but people are coming to find
him and that's what happened with
Jesus's and that's exactly what's going
on that's the parallel with Jesus right
uh they are coming people are coming
looking for Jesus right of every nation
Kindred tongue and people okay so um
whole study on Gentile inclusion we're
going to go ahead and skip that let's
get let's now come to First
Kings uh really from chapter chapters 11
up to chapter 16 and now here's what you
have happening in these chapters
the Kingdom of Israel
divides there is there is apostasy in
the camp um there's a division between
the northern tribes there's a there's a
formation of the northern tribes and the
southern tribes um one under Ram the
other under jobal um there's a spiritual
Decline and then you have the entrance
of Ahab and Jezebel Ahab and Jezebel all
right now y'all help me out here I want
to say something this is something that
stood out this is a spiritual lesson you
can take from that I mean there's always
like a north and a South I know I
thought that was interesting but the
spiritual decline happened after there
was a divide so like we never do well
when we're fighting divided and fighting
against each other like
everyone goes down Absolut I just think
that's something that we can can glean
and learn from there are so there are so
many lessons in MH I mean so when y'all
see yes blessings Joy Constantine and
we're going to move on from there from
Constantine yes Michelle the 1260 years
all of that comes in right here Ahab and
Jezebel are the perfect symbol for the
unification of church and state right um
let me just go back to what I was saying
a little bit earlier we could have spent
a whole study on just the rebellion of
Lucifer in heaven we could have spent a
whole study on chapters 4 through 8 4
through 4 through 8 the the work of
Jesus in building the Temple and it's
parallel to Solomon's work we could have
spent a whole Sabbath
School on the Covenant being finished
and and the Gentiles coming in and the
fame of Jesus going into the world and
how the Gentiles come in as a result of
the work that he has done do you'all see
what I'm saying that there's so much
packed in but we're trying to we're just
trying to see here that there is a
bigger
picture that shows the entire great
controversy like so far we have
literally seen like Whoa We got the fall
of Heaven the fall of Lucifer from
heaven we have Jesus coming to this
earth to do the work of building the
Temple we have the Gentiles coming in as
a result of the work he's doing and now
we're talking about apostasy that
follows right apostasy y follows there's
division apostasy and then the rise of
this Ahab Jezebel
combination and somebody said the
parallel let's go back to the
screen so somebody said the parallel
which they are correct is the Dark Ages
right um as Israel fell into idolatry
the medieval Church era experienced WID
spread apostasy powerful religious and
political alliances suppress true
worship the parallel between ancient
Israel's spiritual Decline and the
medieval Church's era era's apostasy
reveal a recurring pattern in religious
history both periods were marked by
departure from authentic Faith practices
and a rise of influential forces that
hindered genuine worship and Daniel
7:25 is the goto verse for this so yeah
Michelle you cannot make this up right
you cannot make this up vernette I agree
wow wow you cannot make this up um you
see this
apostasy this Jezebel and by the way
when you go to the Book of Revelation we
understand that Jezebel is literally a
symbol of apostate Christianity during
the Dark
Ages
right um listen I always I I say this
quite
often that one of the greatest evidences
that the I think yeah I think the
greatest evidence that the Bible is
divinely inspired is its ability to
foretell the future right but I think a
very close second and arguably even
better than prophecy are these patterns
which you can't make up how in a world
are these
patterns so beautifully laid out m in
all of these different books showing the
same story line from all these different
angles like in Ezekiel it didn't begin
with eternity it began with Jesus as the
son of man being called you know to go
preach to a stubborn and rebellious
people and it ends with the second
coming in first and second Kings it
begins with the fall of Lucifer in
heaven and works its way down so watch
where it goes to right we're we're at
the Dark Ages right now look at what
happen next let's go back to the
screen and look at what happens in First
Kings First Kings
[Music]
um we're GNA go to the next slide First
Kings chapter
17 and
18 y'all this is this is absolutely
crazy not crazy beautiful I'm using
crazy as a word for beautiful
um crazy asn't good yeah it's the story
of
Elijah and the
famine and let me see here how many of
you remember how
long was this
famine and where was Elijah in this
famine so I'm just gonna I'm just going
to wait and I'm going to see if y'all
can tell me how long was this
famine and where was Elijah in the time
of this famine
anybody remember when Elijah said
there's coming a drought upon the
land
um how long was this drought supposed to
last was it seven years
not okay Christina is
close yeah yeah three and a half years
or Anthony
1,260
days Eli the
drought literally lasted
1,260 days and where was Elijah during
this time he was hiding
where anybody
remember was he hiding in the city he
was in the wilderness he was he was in
the
wilderness and what was he what was God
doing for him in the
wilderness providing for him he was
feeding
him all
right does does anyone
realize where this is going let's go
back to the screen let's go back to the
screen uh you will remember that in
Revelation chap
12 that the woman
representing the church is given wings
of an eagle where she flies into the
Wilderness where her places a place is
prepared for her for 1,260
years and what's what's God doing for
her in the
wilderness he is
feeding the church
[Music]
yes the 1260 days three and a half
prophetic years prefigures times of
persecution and hidden Faith this
parallel draws a powerful connection
between the Old Testament Prophet
Elijah and the New Testament Church both
face periods of trial and isolation yet
remain steadfast in their faith the
symbolism of the 1260 days in Revelation
echal to three and a half years of
drought during Elijah's time
highlighting the reoccurring theme of
God's protection and providing and
provision during times of hardship just
as Elijah was sustained in the
wilderness the church finds strength and
nourishment in its spiritual wilderness
this
experience the comparison serves
encourage Believers reminding them that
the period of difficulty in seeming
abandonment are often precursors of
great spiritual Revival and
demonstration of God's power I like how
AI adds a little bit of that stuff in
for
me can't believe AI put this study
together like yes it did like you did it
I mean I'm just saying like I mean
that's pretty
impressive pretty impressive AI this is
this is
absolutely amazing mhm an amazing
parallel yeah it is it
is
so if we recap we're done with First
Kings what have we seen from First Kings
First Kings takes us from the rebellion
in heaven to Jesus coming to this earth
to build the temple to him completing
the temple and the spirit of God filling
the temple the Gentiles coming in and
and coming to to to know Jesus but then
apostasy follows a 1260 year period of
apostasy
MH in which God is protecting his church
during that
time that's that's the whole book of
First Kings right the book that you guys
read and were like man this book kind of
has no rhythm or rhyme to it man this
book kind of like it's just confusing
this is a whole bunch of story of kings
and this King did this and this that and
a lot the only part of First Kings I
like is the story of Elijah other than
that everything else is kind of like huh
what
right no there is like it's just telling
you about the Kings but nothing there is
beauty there is pattern there is
design in the
Bible in every book of the Bible the
great controversy is there like you know
how you say like Jesus is on every page
that's right but the great controversy
is all throughout the Bible it's all
throughout the Bible mhm now now we're
not going to get through all of Second
Kings CU I'm not sure how much time we
have left but um yeah we actually
have about 20 minutes okay we might get
through the book of Second Kings so let
me ask you a question now if if First
Kings
ends
with if First Kings ends with the 1260
then we already know if we're following
the pattern and this is not First Kings
and then first you know uh uh second
Samuel this is First Kings and then
Second Kings so if this these two books
are really one book as it were or a
continuation of the same story then we
might expect that second Kings is going
to pick up where first king leaves off
right so let's see if that's the case
let's go back to the screen and in First
Kings chapters 1 through three we've got
another uh another
segment um or another section that we're
going to this is a section we're going
to cut off so in First Kings it was 1
through3 then 4 through uh 9 then 10
then 11 and then 12 through 16 and then
17 and 18 right those were the blocks
that we could step back and say okay
what is this what are these blocks
telling us these sections of chapters
that we put together oh here's the
picture now we're in second Kings
chapter 1 uh chapters 1 through
3 and here we have a transition of power
from
Elijah to
Elisha so Elijah sends to heaven and a
whirlwind and Elijah listen to me y'all
now El Ela carries on the
mission of
Elijah
Elisha is going to complete or carry on
the mission of
Elijah so if the
church during the Dark Ages Was Elijah
and we're looking at the Protestant
Reformation right MH the reformers those
who were holding on to the truth during
that period of Darkness
if Elijah in this in this uh uh
parallel represents the church who was
hidden during the
Wendy
Sarah do I need to call any other names
if
Elijah represents the church of the Dark
Ages then
Elisha who carries on the work of the
Protestant Reformation who carries on
the work that Elijah began
right must come to represent the remnant
Church of Bible prophecy which is why we
find in Revelation 12 that after the
dragon went to persecute the woman and
saw that he failed in his persecution of
the woman what does he do next he goes
after the remnant which keep the
Commandments of God and have the
testimony of
Jesus wow what in the
world are you
serious have I been missing
this have I been missing this I've been
reading I've read First Kings I've read
Second Kings how did I miss this
yeah yeah sometimes we can miss it
because we're looking at the wrong
things yeah sometimes we can miss it
because our attention has been taken off
of the Bible the the general theme the
overall theme of The Bible it's going to
like when you write a when you're
writing a paper or a story or whatever
you're that Theme Goes throughout the
whole story so the Bible isn't like okay
this is just about this and this is just
about this it's still whatever that is
still is connected to the whole thing
absolutely absolutely
and you know this is why I I just you
know the the passion
for studying the
Bible I genuinely believe if people were
studying the Bible
more all right I'm GNA give an analogy
so here the winds and then the Bible is
underneath is like in the earth okay the
depth of the Bible is in the earth when
we when when our study of the Bible is
on the surface the winds can blow you
away any wind that comes along oh oh
wait what hey yeah and we just get all
riled up and caught up in all kinds of
winds why because our roots are not
they're not underneath the Earth they're
not they're not grounded in the Bible
we're not
so we're not we're not so deep down into
the Bible that winds aren't even
affecting us nice analogy right so the
reason why so many people are affected
by all kinds of Winds of Doctrine and
Winds of hey what what else can we get
caught up in yeah I was G say not even
just Winds of Doctrine we kind of talked
about that a little bit this morning but
just Winds of just life yeah and and
disappointment and frustration and anger
and sadness or whatever
can take you away it can blow you away
from staying connected to God yeah
sometimes it might be hard to know if
God some sometimes people struggle is
God really real is God really there yeah
I think is he hearing me like do he hear
our prayers this when you when you see
stuff like this in the
Bible it leads you to be like well
whatever is happening I know there's a
God right and I know that he's watching
and I know that he has a design that I
can't see right now yes I get it I'm
looking at at what's going on Rami and
man this is chaotic man this this is so
overwhelming God where are you but just
as we read this right we're looking at
First Kings and for many people it just
looks like pure confusion this is just
confusion no there's a Divine Design
here and a lot of us go through life
like that
there's so much you're saying that I
want to just talk about I mean like if
you if someone was just looking in at
Jesus's life and didn't understand the
great controversy and seeing what was
happening to Jesus when he was on this
Earth it would look like there's no God
like this man went and preached about
this God that you know his father that
he loved and he's here and look at him
he's hanging on the cross and he's about
to die you know what I'm saying it's
like when we're going through things
that just don't make any sense yeah and
Jesus had the answers meaning he knew
what he was doing that his death was
part of the plan so he knew but I'm just
saying when people would look in or just
not knowing and so when we when we start
to doubt God is because we
forget God's purpose for yeah this Earth
and for our lives
meaning God never promised
us a perfect life with no trials and no
sadness and no tribulations and all of
that but he did promise us we can have
everlasting life with him and Heaven
yeah do you see what I'm saying like we
when we just focus with on things of
this Earth and then that's when we get
like oh is there a God where is he but
when we start to remember what the real
purpose and the theme yeah then we can
be okay so in any situation if you think
about it like this
every put a one in the chat if those of
you are watching right now are like oh
what in the world like oh wow and I want
to demonstrate something
here put a zero in the chat if you've
read through the book of First Kings and
we're just like I don't get it this
doesn't make sense to me and now after
this study you're like oh wow that's
what it's going to be like one yeah oh
wow that's what it's going to be like
when God shows us in the future MH you
know by the grace of God when we all get
to heaven he's going to be like well
look MH and I we're going to be like oh
wow wow that's why it had to be this way
it had to be this that's why this thing
happened like this and that's why this
thing happened like that and that's why
I didn't get that job and that's why and
that's why and that's why and that's why
it is all God designing without without
intruding on Free Will right but it's
all him designing things to be to give
us the best possible option to be saved
M and that's a powerful thought mm so as
you can
see each one of these segments is a
study in and of itself right it is all
right let's keep moving let's keep
moving all right so that's Second Kings
1:3 so what happens next let's go back
to the screen let's go back to the
screen and
um yeah let's just look at that parallel
very quickly uh let's see let's see
let's
see yeah so bottom of the screen uh the
P the transition from Elijah to from
Elijah to Elisha parallels the shift
from the Protestant Reformation to the
remnant Church of Revelation 12:1 17 um
again we're going to make this this
presentation available you can use it as
your own personal study guide um there
again are several other uh parallels
there but we're going to skip all that
for now um okay in the next chapter
second Kings chapter 4 The Widow's oil
wow the
Widow's
oil The Widow's
oil so what happens in the story were
you gonna there's just a good question
up there I think you should answer yeah
Pastor what about sickness and disease
comes is that part of the planet too so
an enemy has done this is the best way
to sum up sickness and disease this is
not God's doing has done this right but
the Bible says all things work together
for the good of those that love God yes
so despite the sin going on around Us
Des despite sickness despite disease God
is still working right he is still he's
still taking all things bad and working
them to the good of those that love God
yeah so that's why the Bible says all
things work together for the good of
those that love him okay so so all right
so this widow's oil you remember the
story she's in debt yeah um and and so
Elijah tells her get a go go to your
neighbors get vessels from your
neighbors and the one pot of oil that
you have pour it out pour it out into
your
neighbor's vessels that's all she had
and as she poured the more she poured
the more oil MH the more oil the more
oil H what is what so if the if Elisha
now
represents the remnant church then what
is the work of the remnant Church what
is the remnant church called to do to go
into all the world to go to their
neighbors go their neighbors and and
pour oil in their
vessels but I like that the more that
you pour absolutely the more that you
get like the more you you do you teach
and you spread the word like the more
you the more you learn yourself right
and then you the more is given to you
the more is given to you more important
to others the more it's given to you
yeah and that's really that's our
purpose on this that's that's our
purpose on this Earth is to help others
absolutely absolutely to know the Bible
to know Jesus to help them even in their
physical you know needs or whatever like
we are to to minister to them on all
different levels that's right kind of
like the uh Good Samaritan
you found someone you know who was a
need of help anointed him with oil like
just there's so much there m but I want
you to know that the oil stopped when
there were no more
vessels when there were no more vessels
left to be filled the oil stopped a time
is coming where there will be no more
oil left no more oil available right
kind of reminds reminds us of the
parable of the 10 virgins right five had
oil five did not and we again we can go
off into into great detail about this
study can you m like this is do you see
what I mean when I say this is like a
this could easily be a a a 12p part
study just taking each of these segments
yes it def no yes it definitely can
absolutely so and Bernette am man I
agree with that that comment what is she
just said like she was commenting to the
other person about uh sickness when that
does come that can that can be used to
to bring us closer to God and many times
yep it definitely does that good all
right let's go back to the screen let's
go back to the screen uh and we're going
to see once again just the parallel um
so the Everlast the the proclamation of
the Everlasting gospel the holy spirit's
fill the Holy Spirit fills willing
vessels truth is overflowing to all
that's the idea behind uh the parallel
if you will behind this woman with the
oil and and again uh there's more on
this oil you can go through that on your
own now let's get
to let's get to second Kings chapter
five here you have
non's
cleansing
wow you got a cleansing
y'all a
cleansing so if the work of Elijah rep
Elisha parallels the end time Church The
Remnant church and the fact that the
remnant Church is going to all the world
pouring the oil uh uh getting as many
vessels as it as it can pouring the oil
the
conclusion one of the conclusions must
have something to do and let me I let me
not say it I need to give yall some time
to think so will there be a a NE manic I
just made up made up that word a n neic
as a nean okay you're looking at me like
what what cleansing
parallel of a
cleansing at the end of time we have a
prophecy unto 2300 days then shall the
sanctuary be cleansed it all ties in
with the cleansing of the sanctuary the
out PR of the Holy Spirit which is the
process of
purification the purification of God's
people and of those who are coming into
the truth just before the second coming
of
Jesus yeah
yes how are we
doing good I think we can finish this up
mhm I think we can finishes up so we got
the cleansing of the temple let's go
back to the screen we got the cleansing
of the temple
obedience and
um let's see
here okay so we got the cleansing of the
temple uh where we've
got obedience God's word forgiveness
spiritual purification uh all part of
the investigative judgment and we're not
going to mention too much more about
this because we're going to try to see
if we can wrap this up um
okay let's keep going all
right and now we're in second Kings
chapter 6 are y'all are y'all
good so in second Kings chapter 6 we
have the story of
Elisha at and his servant and the armies
have come to get Elisha the armies are
surrounding can y'all are y'all hearing
me the armies are
surrounding
Elisha but Elisha is not worried he
prays that his servant's eyes are open
and when his servant's eyes are open he
sees that they that are with us are more
than they that are with them why because
there are Chariots of Fire surrounding
Elijah and surrounding the Army who's
trying to surround Elijah who's trying
to take
Elijah so what would that
parallel if Elijah is the end time
church if Elijah
is is uh his work the end time Church
work is to pour out the oil
is to fill the
vessels if people are going to be
cleansed is there coming a time of
trouble
blessing absolutely will there be a time
of trouble in
which the armies of this world will be
to surround God's people MH and they
will be delivered and they will be
delivered they that are with us more are
more than they that be with them let's
go back to the screen we're almost there
you guys so 2 Samuel or second Kings I'm
sorry seven and8 um uh deal with uh this
and I should have mentioned ver uh
chapter eight deals with a famine in
Israel so again what we're looking at is
a Chariots of Fire we're looking at a
time of famine a time of trouble and um
this is second Kings chapter 7 and 8 and
now we get to Second Kings uh chapters 9
and 10 and these chapters describe the
downfall of
Jezebel
wait
yes the downfall of Jezebel J who is
anointed king and task with the exe with
executing judgment on ahab's lineage
Jezebel is killed her influence is
eradicated from the kingdom the throne
is eventually secured under joash so
question what is the parallel then of
Jezebel being
killed I would say Satan and the
Thousand Years that he's going to spend
after God's people are
delivered the fall of the Beast the fall
of the false
prophet Babylon has fallen the
destruction of the enemies of God's
people
absolutely that is the paral well mhm
that is a parallel and it is it is
absolutely amazing let me show you this
um we're almost done we're almost there
we just got a little more to
go so I'm going to go back to the screen
and again you know more conversation but
we're GNA we're GNA skip this we're
going to go we're GNA go
to uh all right First Kings chapter 12
the temple is repaired and completed
so I want you to see all the parallels
here the temple is repaired and
completed Jezebel is
killed nonon is
cleansed the oil reaches the
people it's an
amazing if you thought that the Bible
had no rhythm or rhyme to
it you need to think again right it does
it's an amazing parallel you guys note
this note
this so we're
gonna yeah there's more discussion on on
Jo as's
reforms
um the restoration of the true of true
worship all of it is a powerful parallel
but here's what I want to talk to you
about so 2 Kings chapter 13 2 Kings
chapter
13 uh
has a very peculiar story of a man who
touches Elijah's bones dead bones
Elijah's dead bones and um he's
resurrected okay so now you have a
resurrection in the story so y'all help
me out
here yes the dead are resurrected and
absolutely here you have the
resurrection of the Dead in Shadow form
right
right you guys
absolutely mindblowing absolutely
stunning that
this is actually in the
Bible the parallel of the great
controversy is right there in the Bible
for those like oh the great controversy
theme it's you know it's right there in
the
Bible right yeah all over the place all
over the place yeah all over the place
so then we got two sections left in
second Kings let's go back to the screen
what are those two sections then we'll
recap everything so here are the two
sections
left from First Kings
17 in First Kings
17 what you now have is the destruction
of rebellious Israel
what is this
paralleling Israel is destroyed by the
Assyrian
army what's going on here what's the
parallel what do y' all
think what's the parallel of
Israel rebellious Israel being
destroyed think about where we are in
our story line
when Jesus come back and Destroy so it's
the second coming of Jesus right this
would be what we call
uh the
first would be surrounding the first
resurrection
um but this is the destruction of the
wicked which happens when Jesus comes
again the second time right right so
that's a destru of Israel but Second
Kings
closes Second Kings closes let's see all
right let's go back to the
screen um the final chapters of Second
Kings Chronicles the tragic fall of
Judah so Judah is destroyed by
Babylon sometime later years
later there's a second destruction
so if the destruction of
Israel parallel what will happen when
Jesus comes the first
time yes
Jennifer is there a destruction that
takes place sometime
later yes there's a destruction that
takes place at the end of the 1,000 th
years what we call the second
Resurrection or the final destruction of
the
wicked and then the book of Second Kings
ends ends wow and the great controversy
story ends as well and the great
controversy story ends as well
so let's recap
I'm not going to call out the sections
now I'm just going to show you we're
just going to go through the entire
story of first and second Kings in its
parallel form okay in the story of first
and second Kings here's what you have
guys the story of the fall of Lucifer as
he sought to us usurp the
Throne of
God he is cast out of heaven
M this is followed by Jesus coming to
this earth to do the work of building
the
Temple which is us yes when he completes
the temple the glory of God fills the
temple that's that's the day of
Pentecost right the Covenant I'm just
answering the question right they they
can't repent at that time right okay
just they can't repent at the at the you
know probation's already closed and in
the second Resurrection there's no
repentance it's over it's over okay so
um Jesus completes the Covenant
mhm First Kings let me do it over First
Kings chapters 1 through3 that's the
story of Lucifer in heaven right First
Kings chapters uh 4 through eight or
four yeah 4-9 that's the story of
Solomon of Jesus coming to this earth to
build the temple First Kings chapter uh
chapter 10 that's Solomon that's the
Covenant being secured with Solomon
that's the spirit of God falling and
filling the temple and that's Solomon's
Fame going going into all the world
which parallels Jesus who is also by the
way the son of David yes yes yes nerki
Bible all
day chapter
11 Sheba the Gentiles come to the son of
David for wisdom yeah his Fame grows G
calls are coming chapters 12- 16 you've
got this apostasy the rise of Jezebel
and Ahab chapter 17 and 18 you have uh
or I should say the apostate Church from
First Kings chapter 12- 16 or 11-
16 and then it concludes with the story
of Elijah which
parallels the Protestant Church during
the Dark Ages 1,00 260 years that's the
book of First Kings Second Kings picks
up with this transition from Elijah
Elijah to Elisha if Elijah is the
Protestant Reformation Elisha is the
remnant Church The Remnant church that
keeps the Commandments of God and has
the faith of Jesus what happens next
you've got the woman the
woman who is pouring out oil
into into her neighbor's vessels and as
long as there's a vessel to fill is as
long as she has oil to pour right the
church's work in going into all the
world with the Everlasting gospel to
preach Every Nation Kindred tongue and
people and when the last Soul receives
that message the oil will cease to flow
to stop non is cleansed that's second
Kings chapter seven chapter 7 and 8 non
is cleansed paralleling the work the
finishing work
of the investigative judgment the
cleansing of the sanctuary um isn't this
good bread yall it's very powerful this
is a good meal and we haven't even
gotten to the sermon yet this was a good
meal okay so uh n uh we got non and then
after that we have
um
the is it the resurrection was that what
was
next yes cuz the um you got the name in
the cleansing of the sanctuary I'll just
go back I don't want to or the guy yeah
yeah the that guy just touched the the
BB the temple complete that's what's
next yes no no no no no Jezebel's
downfall that's what's next no no no no
no no no
no well remember so non's cleansing
non's cleansing and then you have the
Chariots of fire yes surrounding
Elijah God's people will be protected
will be delivered right so after the
after the fire the the the the CHS of
fire surrounding Elijah's people you
have
um you have the downfall of Jezebel
that's the end of mystery
Babylon
um the end of sin and sinners the
destruction of sin and sinners this is
followed by the temple repaired and
completed God not I shouldn't say
followed by but it is all happening
simultaneously God's church is is
completed fully built the temple is f
the temple is fully
built and then you have the resurrection
power right then you have that's when
the yeah the man touching Elijah's dead
bones yes comes back to life you have uh
which parallels the resurrection of the
righteous dead followed
by the destruction of rebellious Israel
that is the first coming of Christ when
the wicked are destroyed followed by the
destruction of rebellious Judah which is
paralleling the end of the
Millennium where Jesus comes again with
the with the Saints at the end of the
10,000 years and the wicked dead are
ultimately destroyed set up to Jerusalem
who would have thought
who would have
thought that first and second
Kings you know the books that seem like
they don't have any rhythm or rhyme to
it it's just like a whole bunch of
history and people get tired of reading
you know oh the history this is boring
history oh you know what's this book in
here for right who could have
imagined that first and second Kings
contained a prophetic a Divine Faith a
Divine prophetic plan a Divine prophetic
outline
right that demonstrates the
accuracy of the great controversy
theme
yeah it all connects and it makes
you should make your faith even
stronger and you carry these you carry
this faith
you keep going deeper but carry this
Faith throughout life so that when you
want to say is there a God and you is it
is it real you keep going back to you
know what this cannot be coincidence
can't be who who's going to the Bible is
real God like did the authors of the
Bible know like okay well let's put this
story here put this story here no
they're just writing and when people are
just like oh the spirit them to write
right I was going to say people say oh
no humans wrote the Bible know God wrote
the Bible I mean inspired yes God
inspired yeah all
right that's the meal you guys that's
the living Mana meal yes uh for Sabbath
School not for the day for Sabbath
school for Sabbath school it's living
Mana we give it all day during the
Sabbath all right put one in the chat if
uh if you were able to follow along
we're going to go ahead and uh and close
this section out but praise God if
you're able to follow along yeah you
know this is recorded so you can always
go back go back share and you'll get the
the notes as well and um I don't know if
uh we can have the link to the to the
slides put in the chat if possible uh
and if not then we'll just put during
this break we will so stay with us and
we'll put it in in the description of
the um you know when this goes up on
YouTube we'll have it in the description
as well yes yes so let's pray and then
we have some
membership um things to do transfers
transfers yes let's pray let's pray
heavenly father thank you uh for
speaking to us Lord today through the
book of first and second Kings thank you
Lord for giving us uh insight and wisdom
to this book lord um thank you for
speaking to our hearts and Lord I just
pray that you would uh help us to be
ready for that second coming Lord that
um we may Rejoice with you Lord help us
Lord to understand the lessons many of
the lessons that that were shared today
Lord and understand that you are in
control Lord even when things seem
chaotic for the time let us remember
Lord that you are in control and we
thank you for hearing and answering
because we ask this in Jesus precious
name amen amen amen amen
amen yes well guys thank you for staying
with us for through Sabbath school and
then please stay with us through divine
worship service because it's going to be
a blessing but we want to do some
membership transfers and just to let you
know that if you want to become a member
of the living Mana church you can you
can do that there's three ways you can
do that if you are already a member of
the Seventh Day Adventist Church um you
can have your membership transferred to
living Mana church and that makes you
become an official member we love our
viewing audience uh so but if you want
to become an official member um you can
do membership train transfer and you the
email that you see there on the screen
is where you would send that email to um
and um you would follow Patrice will
follow up with you there um also if you
are just learning if you've already been
baptized before and you are just
learning more uh things in the Bible and
what the Seventh Day Adventist Church
believes and you want to become a member
um you don't have to get re-baptized if
you don't want to you can come in by
profession of faith and you can get the
ball rolling with Patrice at that email
as well or if you want to get baptized
if you want to get baptized for the
first time or re-baptized you can um
again send an email uh to Patrice and
we'll get that ball rolling and connect
she will connect you uh with Pastor so
we can start uh setting that process up
as well so those are the three ways that
you can become an actual member of
living Mana church so right now today we
have
we have some transfers we have we have
Let's see we have two second readings
and then we have um a few more first
readings so let's do our first readings
uh first so we have we have Sarah uh mer
Mercers that is transferring out from
living Mana Church to the floral Crest
7day Adventist Church and that is the
first reading
uh for for Sarah and then we have two uh
first readings of people that want to
come into living Mana church and that's
Donna Kirkland she's coming from the
Clarksville 7 Day Adventist Church and
uh Michelle Madson is also wanting to
come into living Mana Church from the
Gladstone Park uh 7day Adventist Church
and so we are um sad to see Sarah go
um but we know she'll still be um a
viewing um audience at times and we want
to welcome Donna and Michelle um after
we do the second reading but we're happy
they want to come to living Mana church
so we have two second readings we read
them last week so we have one second uh
reading that's going out and that's
elizeth rafhael to the Princeton 7day
Adventist Church and then the second
reading for Robert Green who is coming
into living Mana Church from the Santa
Cruz 7-Day Adventist Church been to that
church before used to live close to that
church so we are excited for Robert so
let's go ahead and uh we're going to
entertain a motion for that second
reading for both Liz and Robert so uh if
you are a member we're just going to ask
you to go ahead and put a one in the
chat uh I'm sorry we're going to ask for
a motion first uh so we need a motion
first follow by a second uh and then
once we have that motion in second we
will then go ahead and vote uh and you
can do that by putting a one in the
chat
um
[Music]
so I know I kind of said put that one
first but we do need that motion first
and I'm sure that is
coming yeah I see that Jesse
all right so we've got a motion and uh
let's see if we've got a second all
right so we got a second and uh go ahead
please put that one in the chat um to
approve both transfers all right we got
a second too all
right very good very good all right here
they
come all
right well as they're they're coming in
just want
to uh
say welcome to to Robert Green we are so
happy that you are an official member of
living Mana church we look forward to uh
just you being a part of this church and
getting active and all of those things I
know you've already been here doing
things but we were just excited that you
are an official member now and we will
be doing an official meet and greet at
the beginning of January of all the
members that have come into living Mana
church for the
last half of this year so you know
that's going to be great for the
membership to get to know all of you new
people as well so we are so thankful and
welcome to living Mana church we are
happy to have
you yes yeah amen amen amen amen to that
welcome uh brother green and uh sister
Liz we're sorry to see you go remember
that you're are family um and uh I mean
Liz was almost with us from she was at
the very beginning begin from the very
very beginning um anyway blessings um to
you and Robert again welcome uh we look
forward to uh fellowshipping with you
and um we'll talk about the convocation
again yes at the beginning we will talk
about the convocation at the beginning
of church got an announcement you know
for you guys to be able and the the link
will be the link will be there as well
yeah remember whether you're a member or
not the convocation is open to everybody
everybody convocations open to everybody
if you are a member or you are a viewing
uh audience that is just loves to be
here at Living Mana Church all the time
we'll love to to see you and meet up
with you at the convocation amen so all
right all right the sermon today is part
four of the nine Essentials uh for the
time of trouble so please make sure to
uh if you have not subscribed to the
living man YouTube channel make sure you
do that and also go ahead and share this
link let let people know the sermon is
coming up and again hopefully it will be
by the grace of God it will be another
meal yes if you still have space if you
should you should still have space for
this meal as well so look forward to
seeing you um in Divine worship service
stay with us continue to worship with
us it was the famous French explorer
jacqu custo who once said the sea once
it casts its spell holds one in its net
of Wonder
forever I experienced the truth of this
statement many years ago from my
earliest memories I was always drawn to
the sea I grew up swimming and surfing
cliff jumping and Cave Diving immersing
myself in everything the sea had to
offer the ocean is definitely my
favorite playground
[Music]
for most human beings there seems to be
a natural draw to the water its views
are calming and its Embrace is
refreshing perhaps this natural draw
comes from the fact that we've spent the
first N9 months of our existence in it
and ever since birth it has always been
a part of us 60% of our body is made up
of water it's literally in our blood and
during times of inexpressible Joy or
unspeakable sorrow our deepest emotions
are expressed by the salt water of our
tears for me the ocean is my comfort
place it is my therapeutic Haven where I
can be still and connect with the
Creator it is the only way to visit
another world without leaving planet
Earth the ocean is a water world of
liquid Wonder just waiting to be
[Music]
explored I've had the privilege of
diving in many different parts of the
ocean and the Sea never ceases to amaze
me with its power and Beauty but of all
the waters I've immersed myself in the
waters of Galapagos have definitely been
the most challenging but at the same
time the most
rewarding the Galapagos are a chain of
volcanic islands located 600 Mi off the
coast of Ecuador in the Great Pacific
Ocean the surrounding open ocean waters
drops to a depth of over 9,000
ft the islands are just the tips of
underwater volcanoes that have United in
a vast underwater platform the massive
submarine slopes arise from the ocean
floor breaking the ocean surface into
the island chain that we see and walk
upon today straddling the equator most
would assume that the Waters of
Galapagos are warming and tropical but
there are strong currents that create a
much cooler climate than one would
expect in fact there are three main
currents that Converge on this island
paradise the warm Panama flow coming
from the Northeast the cold Cromwell
currents advancing from the west then
you have the strong humbal currents
surging from the Antarctic South these
strong currents make these Waters
extremely challenging to explore being
located in the deep blue sea and subject
to this convergence of currents
Galapagos is ruled by the brutal forces
of nature but this is also the reason
for the abundance of
life when the underwater currents clash
with the Galapagos platform it shoots up
from the ocean floor bringing a mineral
and nutrient-rich upwelling to the
surface as the equatorial Sun bathes the
mineral Rich Waters it triggers Blooms
of microscopic algae and photoan them
then through the means of photosynthesis
the algae bloom creates 50 to 80% of the
world's oxygen you see without the
currents that cause the bloom of algae
which create the oxygen life on Earth
would be unsustainable the photopin also
forms the foundation of the ocean food
chain it is eaten by Z Plankton which in
turn is eaten by tiny fish which are
then eaten by bigger and bigger fish all
the way up the food chain and this is
the reason why so much diversity of life
big and small intercept here at the
Galapagos it is a major feeding station
in the
[Music]
Pacific so the strong and challenging
currents mixing with the warm equatorial
Sun are basically the lifeline that
sustains all life in this region we are
literally drifting in a current of Life
Oceanic highways of hell that serve as a
marine buffet for the local residence
and traveling Nomads of the
sea diving these strong currents can be
challenging and at times even dangerous
but for those who are up to the
challenge it brings the incredible
reward of seeing the beauty and power of
God up close in living
[Music]
creation as we've drifted with the very
schools of marine life and the currents
of Galapagos I've learned a thing or two
about currents one of them is this there
are currents that lift you up and
currents that pull you down currents
that are safe to drift with and others
you must swim against
currents that bring you to life and
others that can pull you to death in
order to safely dive in the Galapagos it
was not only drift in the right current
but you must also carry a reef hook in
case you encounter a bad current The
Reef hook serves as a personal anchor
that holds you to the rock each diver
must have their own when the currents
are ripping it is not wise to trust in
the anchor of your dive Buddy each must
have their own personal connection to
the Rock in order to be safe each must
choose for themselves to hang on and not
let go for it is our connection to the
rock that enables us to withand the
strong currents seeking to pull us to
our demise we're not strong enough to
stand against the current but the mighty
rock is strong
enough this reality is also true in life
above the surface you see living in a
world of sin seldom do we find ourselves
in perfectly peaceful conditions there
are constant currents of influence
trying to pull us in many different
directions there are hellish influences
that are constantly pulling us down in
Disobedience discouragement and
spiritual death but then there are also
Heavenly influences that are always
seeking to lift us up in trustful Faith
blessed hope and unconditional love you
see in order to be successful in life we
must Choose Wisely which current we
allow to carry us which influence we
will choose to follow sometimes it's
hard to resist the down currents that
are pulling us in the wrong direction
sometimes it's just easier to go with
the surges and urges of our own carnal
flesh and sometimes we don't have the
strength to resist the pull of what is
popular or the flow of what is forbidden
but we can't afford to allow ourselves
to be carried away pulled down by a
world that is drifting in the wrong
direction so in times like these what we
need is to be anchored to the immovable
Rock This Rock
is Jesus yes he is the one the only one
that can rescue us from the currents of
death and carry Us in the currents of
unfailing love to the great Heavenly
Haven
above and so today I encourage you to
allow the rich current of God's love to
lift you up to life more abundant and
life Everlasting and when the down
currents of death begin to pull you away
be very sure that your Anchor Holds and
grips to the solid Rock so hold on and
don't let go and may the rich currents
of blessing continue to
[Music]
flow we hope you've been blessed and
inspired by this new reflections of Hope
episode this episode is one of many
that's been produced all over the world
if you haven't done so yet please give
our video a like share it with your
friends and please follow us on
Instagram Facebook and YouTube if you'd
like to see more inspiring episodes and
get access to much more uplifting
content please go now to
patreon.com revelation of Hope and sign
up to be a member of our patreon page
your monthly support will not only give
you early access to many more inspiring
videos but it will also enable us to
continue to produce more of these
cinematic object lessons from nature our
goal is to produce and release these
episodes much more frequently so please
prayerfully consider partnering with us
so that we may continue to share the
hope of Jesus all over the world thank
you so much for your support Aloha and
marinata
[Music]
e
welcome back living Mana church family
we're so happy that you have decided to
continue to worship with us today please
if you are just joining us and um if you
didn't put in the chat during our first
service where you're viewing from please
put that in the chat now we want to say
a special welcome to you and we love to
see where our viewing audience is is
viewing from if this is your first time
please put a one in the chat we want to
introduce to you living Mana church and
pray that this worship experience will
be a blessing for you so again we're
just so happy that you have chosen to to
come to living Mana church today and to
worship worship with us we are just so
thankful again for each and every one of
you we have viewing uh we have a viewing
audience from all around the world and
remember last week we had somebody from
Serbia and I believe that was the very
first uh time that we had somebody from
Serbia so we just uh just love to see
where people are watching from I know it
looks like we have Ayana from Tobago
Trinidad and Tobago so welcome to living
uh Mana Church we have Denise from
Jamaica Jerry from San Diego Wendy from
Idaho Sarah Jones um is from watching
from Wilson North Carolina hi Maria from
prunell Maria I'm gonna be calling you
in just a few days here just a few days
but it's good to always see you here
with us um and we have uh blessings Joy
from another from Barbados welcome to
living Mana Church
uh Merill from Trinidad good to see you
here uh
Marcel um it's FIS sabados to you I
believe that's Spanish I couldn't see
everything there we have somebody else
from Trinidad well welcome welcome from
that um all the way to that island of of
Trinidad okay and we have Jersey Tri
State Pearl watching welcome Michelle
for from Orlando thank you guys for
letting us know
um yes we have so good to see all of you
here to worship with living Mana church
I just want you guys to know that uh the
way that you can stay connected to
living Mana church because now that you
are um here and you are worshiping uh
with us I want you to be able to to know
what's going on with living man Church
always want you to return back and so
one of the ways that you'll be able to
know when we're going live and when we
have different announcements so that you
can always be in the no you can sign up
to get text that's if you are here in
America you can get
text um and hello to Salt Outreach in
Orlando um yes it's good to have you
here uh to worship with us as well I
know you guys are still putting in the
chat but back to the texting all right
you guys want to get text of when living
Mana church is going live and different
things if you're here in America you can
sign up to get those texts by going to
855 tu
07417 that link is also in the chat so
you'll be able to do that if you are
outside of America which you guys saw
that we have many people who are not
here in America um I'm just looking up
at the screen and I see Barbara is here
from anguila welcome Barbara So if you
are not in America which many of you are
not you can get you can you need to sign
up for Mighty networks Mighty networks
is the way that you are going to to be
able to get all this information that
you need and to have reminders when we
are going live and different
announcements also Mighty networks is
not just that it is also our virtual
Church home our church Home Without
Walls that is where you we build commi
um community and we Fellowship that's
where you're going to learn about all
the small groups that we have you can
join a small group by being on Mighty
network uh reading all about what the
small group is about you know talking to
the the host or the leader of the small
group see if you're interested and you
want to join that is where you can do
that you can meet all your other members
and viewing audience um you guys can
start conversations there get to know
each other a little bit better all that
happens on Mighty Network so if you love
living Mana church and you want to stay
connected if you're in America sign up
for the text if you're around if you're
International you want to definitely do
Mighty networks well you have to do
Mighty networks and in in America you
need to do the tech and mighty networks
because everybody needs to be a part of
Mighty networks because that again is
our virtual Church home for those of you
who are enjoying the programming that we
do here um on living Mana church I just
want you to know that we have children's
programming as well we have an amazing
team that teaches the kids the lmlc kids
are they're learning photo theology
these kids can do things that some
adults can't do with some Bible study
and they're learning not just photo
theology but many other things all the
stories of the Bible they're doing
crafts they're doing things age
appropriate for them and so if you want
your child to get involved with Elmos
kids you can send an email you see that
there or you can sign up with the 855
number text kids and you will uh be able
to sign up and and be start talking to
the leaders of lmlc kids to get your
kids signed up so they can
participate also we just I just like you
know during the first service how you
can become a member of living Mana
church but if you do want to become a
member either through transfer
profession of Faith or baptism you can
send an email to Patrice living mana.
live that's Patrice at Living mana. live
also Pastor Meyers has virtual uh office
hours I saw somebody in the chat in
between uh the programming somebody was
saying how do I get in contact with
Pastor Myers well you can set up a
virtual uh office hours and um again
that email is to Patrice at Living mana.
live Patrice is our church secretary she
will get that set up for you so that's
the way that you can get into contact
with Pastor Meyers we also want to let
you know that you know living Mana
Church you guys know that those of you
who have been here and are very familiar
with living Mana church we are huge on
prayer we are huge on prayer um and
there's you can get your prayer request
in many different ways you can email
your prayer request to pray Living mana.
Church when you join Mighty networks
there's a prayer wall there you can put
your prayer request there or you can
text pray to 8552741386
and it they don't stop until you send a
testimony to say hey God has answered
this prayer and if if you're okay with
it sister amra can read the answer to
your prayer request during a live church
service just to praise God so we can all
praise God together for your answered
prayers so those are the ways that you
can send in your prayer requests to
living Mana church we also want you if
you are subscribed or watching on power
of the Lamb YouTube channel we want you
to go over to the living Mana YouTube
channel and press subscribe and like and
do all those good things there so we are
trying to build that channel as well now
this is something that you guys have all
been waiting for convocation information
those of you who are interested or
planning or wanting to come to the
convocation it's our very first
convocation so the virtual Church living
manage Church is going to be in person
May 1st through the 4th I want you to
start planning for that because we want
to meet you if as many of you uh as
possible pray ask God and if you get it
okay start planning because we want you
to be there um the link is going to be
in the chat but you can also scan that
QR code and as I'm talking please scan
that QR code that will take you to the
website where you can register for the
convocation it will give you information
the other information you're going to
need for accommodations everything is
there on that website if you are not
familiar with how to scan a QR code and
you have your phone please put um you're
going to open up your your camera app
and you're going to point it to that QR
code and then you just press the the
button like you're taking a picture and
that's going to actually capture the QR
code and it takes you uh to that link
again the the link for the the website
where you can register and get
accommodations as well is in the chat at
this time as I speak so all of that is
there uh definitely sign up to get those
text alerts because you're going to be
getting a lot more information and just
reminders and again the link to where
you can go to sign up so you can get it
there you'll be able to get it on Mighty
networks so we want you to be a part uh
of in we want you to know and we want
you to be part of the convocation so we
can fellowship with you in person we're
so thankful for our online church but
it's going to be nice to come together
and get to talk to you oneon-one and for
all of you from all around the world
that we're so excited for what God is
going to do during that time we are also
excited because tomorrow like I
mentioned we have uh the LM Mo Christmas
party this is our third one guys we've
it's always a lot of fun but this is our
third annual living Mana Christmas party
it's tomorrow and it starts at 5:00 p.m.
central Time and I uh believe that that
is on alter live so you're going to want
to download that app alter live if you
have not you are going to also again
want to sign up sign up for reminders
and um so that you can get reminded
tomorrow but if you sign up for the text
and and on Mighty networks you will be
reminded
tomorrow when things are starting to
happen because we know this is the
Christmas time uh where everybody's busy
but you can always have living Mana with
you because you could just be carrying
living Mana um broadcast on your phone
and you can just stop what you're doing
or even you don't have to stop what
you're doing but you can just turn it on
so you can be able to participate and
just listen and be a part of it we'd
love to have you to have you there um I
know the last two uh Christmas parties
have been a lot of fun especially Bible
Jeopardy is a ton of fun to play with
you guys like it's a lot of fun so
you're not going to want to miss that
Pastor Myers will be sharing uh a few of
his uh poetry yes he writes poetry guys
and um I'm doing something simple but
I'll be there as well but you're
definitely not going to want to uh miss
that so we look forward to having you
there and celebrating um Christmas with
the living Mana
Church also power Wednesday we have a
special power Wednesday coming up this
Wednesday that is Christmas but that's
how serious our prayer team is about
prayer it's Christmas and they're doing
a special prayer Christmas Power
Wednesday and that is on Christmas and
that is happening at the regular time
the 6:30 p.m. central Time so after
you've opened the gifts hopefully had a
great meal with your family and all of
those type of things you can come to
power Wednesday and come and pray and
praise God with our prayer team uh
together uh on Christmas day so look
forward to having you guys there for
that as well you know I wanted to how
many of you put a one in the chat if you
really enjoyed last week when we did the
announcement for loli Global and you
actually got to see a video of Pastor
Meyers uh speaking I believe that was in
Korean last week well today you're going
to get another taste of that and he will
be sharing in Arabic and that is what
living Mana Global uh does is that we
want God has called us as we learned in
Sabbath school and we did all those
parallels with the great controversy
that he has called us to go into all the
world and we want to go into all of the
world um in the languages of the world
and so we have living Mana church has
purchased a program so that we are able
to right now do seven different
languages we want that to grow as well
and as you saw last week it's not so
simple where it's just
um just um just transferring Pastor
Meyer's um sermons the audio part but
also the slides um have to be translated
as well and then we have proof readers
who know that what the how the program
has translated his message makes sense
because that is their native tongue and
so it's a whole process and um so we
have proof readers and an editor that
does all of that so we want to just show
a sample of that again to today and I
believe that this is in
Arabic for
[Music]
saying wow that's or in the chat I
should say that's really cool and yes
that is really cool uh that we're able
to do that we praise the Lord for those
uh the cap the capabilities that we're
able to to do that um and to go into all
the world and the languages of the world
but as you can see that takes time to be
able to edit and put that together like
the slides we obviously couldn't read
what in the world that was saying and we
definitely could not understand what
Pastor Myers was saying but uh this is
the mission of living Mana church so
when you um first of all these are up on
YouTube so if you know someone that
speaks Spanish or Korean or French or
Arabic Hindi and I'm forgetting the last
two guys I'm sorry but when you go there
you'll see the different languages that
you could share those messages is um if
they are more comfortable in hearing it
in uh their language then definitely
please share those uh messages to with
them um and they can spread it to other
people who who speak that language as
well but as you consider giving to
living Mana Church remember these are
things that we are doing um that this is
part of our um local church budget those
type of things come out of our local
church budget so as you want to support
the church just always know that we are
all about evangelism and spreading this
uh word to all the into all the world
this message of Jesus um and his Saving
Grace so um just remember living Mana
doing all of these things into all the
world and if you're wanting to give uh
virtually this is how you're going to do
that you go to adventistgiving.org
and you're going to to click on the
right hand corner you're going to put in
living Mana church then click in the
right hand corner and you're going to
get a virtual tithe in envelope there
you'll be able to to see where you can
give your tithe your tithe supports the
northeastern conference which living
Mana church is um a church a part of the
northeastern conference you'll also see
the local church budget that line is
that what helps to support living Mana
church and the things that we are doing
here and the mission it helps to support
the mission that God has called living
Mana church too there's also a
benevolence fund where we are able to
take take funds from there and to help
people who are in need um and so that
and there's other things also on that
tithe envelope that you can give to as
well and so definitely take time to go
to adventistgiving.org put in living
Mana church and then the rest is
self-explanatory and give as God is
leading you if you are wanting to uh
send in a check you are you are able to
do that as well you can mail it uh to
live to living a church and that's P box
428 Owens Crossroads Alabama
35763 and you will uh just please I
should say rather uh put a note in the
um with your check to say where you want
it to go if this is for um the local
budget if this is for Tai if this is for
benevolence fun or if it's for both
whatever it is please put it in there so
we can make sure that it goes to the
right place and is directed to where you
want it to go and so those are the two
ways that you can give to support living
Mana church we are so thankful to all of
you for supporting this church this was
this church was just a dream it was just
a dream and God blessed it to become a
reality and this reality has been here
for almost three years and so we are so
thankful uh to all of you to for
supporting living Mana church and making
it a reality and um we know that through
your giving and your faithfulness your
support and your prayers that is what
has uh caused living Mana Church to be
here and to be a blessing to so many
people around the world and that is with
God's blessing upon the church and so we
just want to pray for you um and for all
of just we just want to pray for you and
we want to thank you uh for everything
that God has allowed you to do for
living Mana Church and we just want to
pray for this world um because we know
this world is just um just not in a good
place and so we just want to pray and
ask God to to give us the strength to do
what we need to do in this world so he
can come again if you would just bow
your heads with me as we
pray Heavenly Father Lord I thank you uh
for the Sabbath Lord I Thank you for
this time of year where we get together
and spend so much time with family it is
a blessing Lord to be able to do that
and I am you know not remiss I'm not you
know that naive to think that uh some
people really don't enjoy this time of
year because maybe they don't have great
relationships with their family Lord I
pray for those who go through some
seasonal uh depression during this time
um just want to lift them up to you or
maybe there's those people those out
there who don't have family that they
can spend time with Lord I ask that you
will bless them during this time um Lord
maybe they have friends or others that
they can spend time with Lord or maybe
they'll just spend time with you Lord
show them a supernatural love that they
are not feeling alone and lonely during
this time lord I want to pray uh for
every viewing audience and every member
of living Mana Church Lord I pray over
their family pray over their marriages I
pray over their health just asking that
you will bless them in these areas Lord
Lord you know what each individual needs
Lord I pray that you will provide that
and that their relationship with you
will grow even closer Lord I Thank you
for living man a church and all that
it's able to do it's only because of you
and the blessing that you have given to
living Mana church and how you see us
through Lord this is your church you
called it into existence you keep it
thriving and strong and together Lord
and so we thank you for that we are
about to enter into a new year here very
soon Lord and we just pray pray that you
will in 2025 Lord that you will take us
to the next level that you will help us
to correct anything that needs to be
corrected and make it even better and
that you will just continue to bless
this church Lord I pray for pastor
Meyers as he has a message from you for
us and I just pray that it will touch
every heart that will hear this message
now live and after we ask all these
things in Jesus name amen
hello I'm Hugh Wesley carington prayer
Ministries leader for the northeastern
conference in January we'll begin our 10
days of prayer and so the theme for 2025
is but when you pray our 10 days of
Prayer Will begin January 8 2025 and
we'll end with our Sabbath celebration
January 18th and so we're encouraging
you to visit
www10 daysof prayer.org to get the
readings for each night and you need to
know that the readings are available in
a variety of languages and as we did
last year for 2025 we're teaming up with
health ministries and joining me today
is our health ministries leader well I'm
Joshua deine health ministries director
for the northeastern conference and I'm
excited to team up with my good friend
and colleague Dr Carrington to Kickstart
your 2025 with a happy healthy and holy
beginning in Daniel chapter 1 Daniel and
his friends chose a simple plant-based
diet they drank water and prayed three
times a day the result they were found
10 times smarter and healthier in the
New Testament the disciples prayed for
10 days in the upper room and were
filled with the Holy Spirit well our
North American Division has declared
2025 as Pentecost 25 so we encourage you
to start the year feeling good looking
good and filled with the Holy Spirit
here are five simple things you can do
for the 10 days one eat a plant-based
diet two drink water instead of juice or
soda three walk daily four sleep by 10
p.m. five pray like Daniel those who
embrace the Daniel's diet have reported
incredible victories shedding tongs
balancing blood sugar lowering
cholesterol and saying goodbye to
brainfall you are not alone partner with
your family your friends or your church
and let's transform together start
2025 strong yes so we encourage you to
join us each night online from 7:30 to
8:30 p.m. just 1 hour you'll get health
nuggets to encourage you in your food
choices you'll receive and we'll review
the readings each night we'll pray and
praise God together across our
conference and so as we go through the
10 days of prayer and as you challenge
yourself with the Daniel's diet we we'll
also pray each night for the North
American Division Pentecost 2025
initiative so let's begin the
transformation one prayer one meal and
one step towards a healthier more
fulfilling life in Christ that's right
and so for more information visit nec's
website or NE health.org website or
reach out to your church clerk so what
are you waiting for start your 10 days
journey of prayer and help now it's your
ticket to a happy healthy and holy
2025 let the journey begin
[Music]
could have been a night just like this
one the
air filled with
anticipation and that
light so bright in the night sky that it
beckoned for Shepherds and wise men to
follow imagine to their surprise when
they arrive and find a tiny baby laying
in a manger surrounded with nothing more
than farm
animals how could this be their
King how could the savior of the world
be here in this
place and yet they were
compelled they bowed down right there
and worshiped him you see they knew that
something beyond comprehension had just
transpired the hope of all mankind has
just shown up before them that Jesus
although a baby had come for you and for
me he came to give us a hope and the
future he came so that we might have joy
and light he came so that no matter what
circumstances we find ourselves in all
we have to do is call on his name and we
would be saved this is the story of
Christmas this is the story of the
greatest gift ever
given the story of a king the savior of
the
world born in a manger for you and for
me
[Music]
night
holy
night oh
is
your mother and
child
[Music]
holy Soul
tender
and
s in heaven
[Music]
sleep
night sh
[Music]
[Applause]
the from
[Music]
Heaven sing
hallelu
Christ the savior is
oh Christ
[Music]
the here at Living Mana we bear each
other's burdens when you need support or
prayer when you're feeling
discouraged or alone or
anxious you don't have to face life
struggles alone
[Music]
let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
Grace to help in our time of
need the Lord is close to the
Brokenhearted and saves those who are
crushed in spirit
[Music]
amen greetings Saints of the most high
God welcome to another living Mana
prayer and praise time as always I am
here with my lovely bride amra and we
give God praise for you and for this
opportunity to be able to serve you in
this uh great capacity want to send out
our our love to all of you who have
prayed for us and continue to pray for
us as we pray for you thank you so much
for all of your shout outs there and uh
I didn't see a whole lot of Praise
prayer request in the chat today but I
promise you that if they're there we're
getting them and we're praying over them
and and want to encourage you to
continue to send your uh your uh prayer
requests and your praise reports uh to
uh pray at uh Living mana. Church uh did
want to shout out my brother Robert
Green uh welcome to living man of family
brother you've already been here as
first lady said and been active and
thank God for you A lot of people don't
know that you are a former coworker of
mine and so uh it was it was always a
blessing working together with you
brother in The Great Outdoors and doing
all that stuff we were doing and uh now
we're here in the kingdom of God serving
together here so uh man what a blessing
what a blessing also wanted to remind
you all when we're talking about the
congregation uh our producer sister
Patrice who's also the Church secretary
and the living man board member reminded
us that the tech team will be at the
convocation so that's brother Colin
brother Josh brother Gavin our Great
Tech Team going to be there uh uh uh in
action doing what they do and thank God
for their work and their labor because
uh they are awesome and they get they
get it done so uh we love y'all and
thank God for you there we never we're
never forgetful of you also want to send
a special shout out to Sister Pauline
and and her good buddy Benjamin Lisa
this is Lisa Clark's Grand nephew on
Monday will be their birthday and if any
of you so happy birthday Sister Pauline
we love you you know we love you you're
dear to us my big sister and so if any
of you are also having birthdays uh
coming up between now and next Sabbath
when we get back want to say happy
birthday to you have a great have a
great uh holiday experience and and
listen you know
um our first lady said something that's
really real you know she mentioned
seasonal depression and for a lot of
people you know this time of year is
anything but a joyous time of year and
and I'm I'm I know we don't have a lot
of time so I'm not going to get too much
into this detail but I can remember my
worst Christmas ever I was in the most
beautiful place on the planet I was in
Singapore China it was my first time
away from home I was in the Navy and I
was just I don't know this wave of
depression just came over me I don't
care how beautiful it was I just felt
lost longing to be back to the one place
I was spending most of my life trying to
get away from that was home because all
the trauma and the hurt and the memories
that from there but
then fast forward years later I was I
found myself in prison y'all know my
testimony and I want to tell you the
best Christmas up until well 2017 when I
met pastor nante and and I met my my
lovely bride amra we you know prior to
that I hadn't had a Christmas that
wonderful but one of my best Christmases
of all time was spent in one of the
darkest most demonic and oppressive
places on the planet and you know what
that was that was in prison it was
because Jesus Jus was there for real
alive and in my life and I had
experienced that Pentecost the brothers
was talking about that we're going to be
uh seeking for uh in our 10 days of
Prayer in 2025 that Pentecost happened
in my life and God became really real to
me and it didn't matter what my
circumstances was like and so during the
Sabbath school today pastor and first
lady gave us really and the antidote
reminded us of the antidote to
depression and to heartache and to
loneliness and to spare and hopelessness
the Bible says in Romans chap 15:4
whatsoever things that were written a
four time were written for our learning
that through patience and comfort of the
scriptures we might have hope that's
Romans 15:4 look that up and so when we
are reading back if we know our Doctrine
and we know the great controversy and we
know the message God has given us in the
Everlasting gospel and present truth
here in the remnant church then when we
go back after we've become familiar with
with our message and then we go back and
read in the Old Testament and we see
those parallels those men had no idea
that their lives were playing out the
story his story his story is his story
and and and when we go back and see it
we think wow this is amazing and it
gives us great comfort it gives us great
hope it Roots us grounds us and settles
Us in what God has given us and we
realize wait a minute I don't have this
message this message has got me and it's
always had Me Through the Ages
Hallelujah and God has been our dwelling
in ages past so here like I said not
here to preach but here to preach so
thank God for you know living Mana thank
God for the word he's given us thank God
for all of you Saints love y'all my my
warrior sisters in the chat y'all know
who you are love all of you I ain't
gonna do no roll call today no oh you
know what what I think I'm gonna do a
roll call today
amen then thank you for all those in the
chat who are welcoming us aana
Jamie Patrice ni Hallelujah we have
Robert Plant Lisa Clark Joanne Elder
Robert Jackie Lisa Marie
Michelle anyone else well you know was
you you done started it now so I you
know what we cannot not have a roll call
we cannot so you know what okay brother
Graham what you know I see you right
there in that chat brother sister Rich
sister Denise you're there sister Sarah
Jones you're there love all of y'all
Patrice Nicole We're Not Gonna Forget
You Katrina love you my sister love you
amen uh uh who Christina I see you in
the chat great praise God thank you guys
for your greeting this morning love
y'all sister Joan don't think we
overlooking you and and from beautiful
sunny San Diego you know who you are
sister Jerry you're there love all of
you all and uh see I don't like doing
roll calls sometimes I feel like I'm I'm
leaving somebody out then I can start
trying to call out everybody okay well
we love you all living man of church we
love y'all we love y'all praise God Amen
and so now we're going to do some praise
reports yes absolutely we've heard some
awesome praise reports I've been reading
some and matter of fact there was some
came in you know she does the praise
work but I was I was looking at some we
if we don't get to them this week we'll
definitely get to them next week by the
grace of God
before I share praise reports just a
reminder that if you have a prayer
request or a praise report you would
like to join our prayer team or a
special ops group under our prayer team
Umbrella Please send an email to pray
Living mana. Church if you have a
request for a special ops team for
someone or yourself please send an email
to spec Ops that's SP P Ops at Living
mana. Church if you would like to join
the women's ministry on Mighty networks
please send an email to women
Wen Living mana. Church and if you would
like to join the mighty Men's Ministry
please send an email to seven loaves
that's s v n l o a v s Living mana.
Church amen let me send a special shout
out to brother Ross and Gina Brower they
were teaching Sabbath school at one of
the local churches today they're living
man of family uh prayer team leadership
I mean they're just pillars here and
want to say we love y'all and thank God
for you I also want to send a shout out
to brother Quincy so Quincy if you get
to play this later and see the Bri one
know that we're thinking about you and
we love you we're praying for you didn't
have internet where you were but we we
love you my brother you're always living
man of family and finally sister Hattie
anytime you put the word young in front
of our names yeah you gonna get a
special shout out okay amen so our my
company I'll take it I'll take it my
company had a little holiday get
together yesterday and and you know
families went and uh us youngsters there
was someone there that called us young
people and said I said we think we she
says in your 30s and I was thinking now
come on man but thank you for that that
was that was flattering that was very
flattering she about fell over I told
said you know what um uh I'll be 60 in
two years and uh so you know uh thank
God it gives you the opportunity to tell
the tell the world about what God's been
doing so or tell the world your age you
know one or the other amen all right
let's get to these praise reports shall
we all right from Patty Cardinal praise
the Lord with me for my husband Juan
berotti has finished the cell transplant
and he is free of lymphoma cancer amen I
do not explain more because I feel lousy
please pray for me that the Lord have
mercy on me and remove the Satan
possessed enemies that torture me and
Terry will be praying for you Patty for
that piece but we praise the Lord for
your husband and his cancer free
diagnosis from brother James praise
report thank for the prayers sent up I
just got my car back after being a
little time without transmission is
fixed praise God yes yes from Annette
Rivas I have a praise report I had
mentioned a few weeks back I was
scheduled to have a CT scan with
contrast when I set up my appointment I
reached out to the hospital that would
be doing my CT scan and asked if there
was any financial assistance even though
I have health insurance through my
husband's work the amount I needed to
pay after insurance was
$1,250 and unfortunately I did not have
it I wanted to cancel my appointment but
I was prompted to reach out to the
financial office and they told me to
submit an application from financial aid
my application was approved and my bill
was dropped to
$50 I just wanted to give all honor and
glory to God for his faithfulness praise
God Amen praise go and lastly from
Angela Perry Oh Hallelujah we have been
praising with Angela for the last
several days praise report most of you
know I've had some major issues with
squirrels living in my apartment Attic
in walls it was so unbearable I left my
apartment in July to stay with family
the management gave me special
permission to break the lease but I had
no place to go by faith a couple months
ago I went and purchased moving boxes
tape Etc I started packing with no place
to go I called one apartment this week
to check the status of my application
and the lady said and I quote we are
looking for someone to move into a
two-bedroom apartment praise God I
followed her instructions and today I
picked up my keys that was yesterday
praise God it only took God a few days
to Manifest this apartment I am so happy
check out my video on YouTube and mighty
to see the tour of the apartment what a
beautiful Christmas gift from the Lord
and thank you for your donations God
bless you glory to God somebody amen
amen amen watch we was in the same room
we shouting together right now y'all
because
listen you know we we've been praying
with beautiful sister Angela and now
ever since she came to living Mana she's
such a gift such a leader such has such
a car Charisma and let's the Holy Ghost
lead her in the word and in encouraging
everybody and to see her season come you
know let that be encouraged to somebody
encouragement hold on your season is
coming it's coming don't give up don't
give in don't give out don't throw in
your towel don't throw your towel out
hold on hold on because your season is
coming sints amen amen and you know um I
was also thinking you know first lady
was talking about this in the beginning
you know about life you know God has a
plan he's already written a plan we
don't have to take control of it
sometimes the journey might look a
little bit crazy we be like Lord where
you going with this I mean come on now
you know but God has it you know and and
so when we go back and look at these
amazing parallels and we see down
through history in the Book of Ezekiel
we started the day we did first and
second Kings you know and pastors using
them them uh verse genetics to show us
how it all connects and how it's all
related listen what that does is that
builds up confidence and Assurance in us
that wait a minute God's got this story
written out the plan for my life is laid
out he has not planned any defeats for
me but Lord help me get in this word and
get in my on my knees and get filled
with the power of the Holy Ghost so that
I can be in tune with you and see what
it is you have done and where you're
taking me all the peace of God that will
fill our hearts the supernatural peace
we call it crazy peace here and the
Bible has promised us that that that
pain that peace will guide and keep our
hearts and minds and so amen listen
don't let it just be a bunch of words
let's pull let's press in the spirit and
let's press to our God and give him
glory and praise for what he has done
listen Saints it is real it is real it
is true and we know as it gets rough
sometimes that's why we continue to pray
that's why we're committed to prayer the
living man of Prayer Warriors know
they've been called anointed and
appointed and and God is doing a Great
and Mighty work and so for you want to
say we love you we we we count it a
blessing we count it an honor to be able
to uh to pray and I'm going to tell you
something this church prays all the time
time time and uh I thank God for it I
think last night we got on a call at 6
and we didn't get off that call till
like what nine something 10 it was like
2: in the morning for some people
starting to be an all night prayer
meeting Hallelujah and we're looking
forward to having more of these prayer
groups throughout living man we'll talk
more about that later in the future with
some things that God's going to do that
we can have such a tight close-knit
family where we're just edifying one
another encouraging one another and
building one another up carrying one
another's burdens and just helping each
other to see uh uh life more clearly
that you know sometimes you might look
at your trial you've seen it from your
perspective but God will bring a brother
and sister alongside you filled with the
Holy Ghost to encourage you your
Elizabeth to help you birth that thing
that's going on inside of you so I I
want to encourage you too you know I
know the holidays are very um just
stressful and depressing and and lonely
for many people plug into the community
I know power Wednesday is going to
happen on Christmas evening I believe at
the regular time yeah if you are feeling
down come to power Wednesday that's
right I know there's probably folks that
aren't going to be there because they're
with their families but it is a safe
space where people can come and just
fellowship and pray together and be
encouraged so don't be afraid to plug
into the church and our small groups we
have so many ways of being part of this
family where you never have to be alone
right and let me just say this in in the
the the most family homely way I can we
is your family so so plug in right here
we are your family here living Mana we
love you we have a beautiful program set
up our beloved sister Gigi who's just uh
awesome awesome at putting together
these things she's put together a great
program and by the way sister Gigi
experienced her own praise her own
Miracle this this Christmas you know uh
since she was here at Living Mana she's
been doing such a great work got
baptized joined the church just been
growing and blossoming like a flower
growing more and more and her mom came
and visited a few months ago y as you
recall and was in church with us and
fellowship with her you know and you
know this Christmas Gigi got a gift from
her mom first time in 20 years oh I mean
and you know that's just a beautiful
fruit you know to be manifested want to
thank you sister Gigi we love you you
know it you know it looking forward to
seeing you in Orlando by the grace of
God and I want to pray let y'all know
those of you who every time we mention
the convocation the Lord whispered this
in my ear I believe every time we
mention that convocation there's
somebody watching you get a little knot
in your stomach and you think man I hope
I can make it I want you to remember
that praise report that our sister had
when she said you know what um sister
Anette said that my my even though I had
my husband's benefits insurance it was
still going to cost me
$1,230 out of pocket and then she went
and God showed her favor ended up
costing her 50 bucks you know God look
God can do it all the resources are his
if it's in his plan for you to be there
he will make provision sister Jackie
shared something with us in the Huddle
this morning says that when we surrender
to God's service there is no position we
can find ourself in that he has not made
provision for amen I think that's from
Christ object blessings you want to keep
that in that that's a promise a powerful
promise God has made provision for you
as you are surrendered to him doing his
will amen amen amen let's go to the
throne of grace Saints and pray and
beseech our father that he would uh move
on our behalfs and raise us up and
strengthen us and allow us to be all
that he's called and created us to be
today so Lord we come to you again today
Lord with joy in our hearts Lord no one
knew this but Amar but when we started I
was feeling a little bit under the
weather but Lord as I begin to just
yield to you and move forward and step
out in faith with you Lord I find myself
a bit over the weather right now raised
up to sit in Heavenly places in Christ
Jesus because that's the reality of
where we all are and we give you praise
for that today as we draw near to the
throne of grace as we draw near to your
presence and Power thank you God for
your Supernatural infilling in your
people today in Jesus name thank you for
the blood of the lamb slain from before
the foundation of the word there is no
sorrow there is no sin there is no
failure Lord God no blunder on our part
that you have an already made provision
for and thank you for your great con uhh
forgiveness as we come confessing our
sins before you today thank you for
restoring us Lord God to your to to
fellowship with you and putting us in
right standing with you it is by faith
in your goodness we put our faith in
your faithfulness we put our faith in
your mercy we put our faith in your love
we put our faith in your willingness
Hallelujah to touch us and to heal us
and to save us from the gutter most to
the uttermost oh Lord thank you that you
are greater than all our sorrows thank
you that you're greater than all of our
sickness and sadness thank you that you
are greater than all of this seemingly
impossible circumstances that we often
find ourselves in Lord thank you
Hallelujah that you have purchased it
and because of the sacrifice of Yeshua
hamashia Lord because of your son's
sacrifice you have the right to disrupt
our program you have a right to disrupt
the plans of the enemy you have a right
to save heal touch and deliver you have
a right to move Heaven and Earth on
behalf of your people and God we give
you praise today Hallelujah that you're
more than able Glory and Honor be unto
you Lord we rest in you today we worship
you today let God arise and let his en
may be scattered in the mighty and
Majestic name of Jesus thank you for the
Sabbath School word today the Sabbath
school lesson today Lord I pray create
in us a hunger Lord break this
diabolical spell that the prince of the
power of the air has put on the hearts
and minds of us Lord that we become so
enchanted and entangled Lord God and and
and and and and wrapped up and in Shroud
in the cares of this world and the
things of this world that only serve to
distract us may we have a hunger and a
thirst and an interest in your word
don't let us be disillusioned Lord God
from the Everlasting gospel but to get
in your word and have our minds blown
like we did this morning when we see
these parallels when we see these truths
down through history that history is his
story it is your story God written out
in the lives of your people in ages past
that we have nothing to fear but that we
would forget that you are the true and
faithful witness the true and faithful
Shepherd leading us oh Lord God you have
been our hope in ages past and you will
be our hope forever and ever and we give
you glory for it today in Jesus name
thank you for that word Lord I want to
thank you for I'm asking you for a
miracle for all of our members and
family and friends who are experiencing
sickness and afflictions today because
we we're constantly hearing about it and
Lord God may not have enough time to
mention them all but we know you know
them all you we've read that so many
times in the gospel that you healed them
all and so we lift them all up to you
right now in the name of Jesus Miracles
over the holiday season restoration and
healing Lord God to bodies Lord God
which are your temples the place you
came to dwell this holiday season this
Advent season when many people are
talking about Jesus and remembering
Jesus I pray that your people will find
their temples when you came to
Tabernacle amongst men when you came to
live in this physical body Lord that's
what this Advent is about and so father
we pray heal these bodies come now Lord
Jesus come now and heal your your people
touch your people and raise them up in
Jesus name and then oh Lord God give us
the wisdom to cooperate with you to make
wise decisions concerning our lifestyles
and our diets Lord God and what we eat
break the spell off of us Lord that has
us so enchanted with some of the uh
allurements and enticements of this
world in Jesus name we pray Lord God and
Lord we know you ain't trying to take uh
the good life from us you're not trying
to take good things from us your word
says only the thief cometh not but but
the skills steal kill and destroy but
you came that we might have life and
life more abundantly and so Lord help us
to know just what is good and to choose
that in Jesus mighty name and oh Father
give us control over our appetites
because lord it's been said already Lord
in Inspiration that if we cannot control
our appetite then how in the world are
we going to get victory over sin and so
break the spell in Jesus name we pray
father and God I want to thank you for
brother artel Peters is praying for
biblical retention that he will be able
to hold your word in his heart and in
his mind Grant him that in the mighty
name of Jesus I know another man Lord
God that was involved in so much mess
and Madness drugs and alcohol and you
have healed his mind and renewed his
mind and restored his mind and restored
him to sanity Lord God and he's here to
testify today that you are indeed a mind
regulator Hallelujah you will heal the
sinick soul God and you will put your
word in the hearts of your people who
love you and desire in Jesus name Lord
want to pray for J El and his family
Lord God Touch This familyes surround
them raise them up Lord may your
blessings be upon them and in their
house in a special way today Lord we
thank you for Sister Pauline and brother
Quincy Lord he uh shuts that truck down
he's driving again but he'll shut that
truck down on Sabbath but he stopped at
a truck stop that doesn't have the
internet we don't we can't imagine how
that is today but it is and so father we
pray that brother Quincy will at least
be able to tune in later that he will be
able to be in the word and in prayer
that he would know your presence with
him your comfort with him supernaturally
somehow get him connection I pray he
heard this word anyway in this very
moment in Jesus mighty name and God I
want to thank you for brother Anthony
Ferguson and Sister Janice Ferguson
there in bise continue to be with them
and bless them Lord God they're dear to
us and near to us though they be miles
apart pray for their great um for their
granddaughter Ramy who's in the hospital
right now dealing with depression father
cheer her heart up Lord God it it don't
have to make no sense why let me even if
there's no evidence in her circumstances
no evidence in her situation to show why
she's got joy give her Joy anyway
unspeakable joy you said you give us a
joy and a peace that the world did not
give to us and the world can't take away
so Lord God you have purchased the right
to fill our heart with overflowing Joy
right now and we pray that also for
anyone else experiencing depression
right now somebody watching right now I
know it Lord is tempted to be depressed
tempted to feel alone tempted to feel
that they're not worthwhile but but
Jesus you said you would have come to
this earth if it was just for one amen
hallelujah I pray that they would have a
connection with you in this very moment
Lord that they wouldn't think it's just
Terry here praying but Lord God because
Terry don't know what to pray but God
You' have given us the Holy Ghost to
make intercession with us with groanings
which are too deep to be uttered some of
the pains and some of the agony and some
of the torment and torture that
somebody's going through right now they
can't even put into words but thank you
Lord Jesus you know you know Lord God
and have been touched with the feelings
of our infirmities and you're able to
save and SAR those that are needing you
in this hour and so we thank you and
praise you right now in Jesus name thank
you for our beloved sister esita white
praying for her family for Spiritual
healing and for feeling physical healing
and that they would might walk closer
with you Lord God thank you Lord Jesus
you are indeed the desire of our souls
Lord and so we praise you and our
beloved sister Jamie Lord has reminded
us to pray for Tammy who's in the
hospital uh recovering from a pneumonia
Lord and we just pray right now touch
her lungs fill her lungs Lord clear her
lungs up from that infection Lord God
and may she find strength get her blood
count up Lord God in Jesus name touch
her Lord God and may she breathe
smoothly again Lord God in Jesus name
thank you those antibiotics they're
giving her just go to work on her Lord
God Hallelujah in Jesus name sister
Katie s was uh had a job interview on
Friday precious father and she is
believing for her first job God we're
rejoicing we can't wait to get the
praise report back lord God to know that
you showed her favor Lord God if this is
indeed your will her job her first job
but if not God give her something better
sometimes you you know means you held it
up today so you can double it up
tomorrow whatever the case may be Lord
bless her be with her and give her peace
and Brent who's a father and a husband
is experiencing depression and Lord
we're hearing a lot about this
depression but your word say said Lord
God Hallelujah at that advent of Christ
Lord your your host of angels declared
peace on Earth Good Will toward man and
I pray God Hallelujah to Camp your
angels around all your people that is
experiencing this these lies of the
devil and this depression Lord that they
would be uh receive your joy God and
they would be a a living witness and a
living testimony that the Lord came and
gave me joy and My Darkest Hour
Hallelujah in Jesus name and father we
thank you for sister Patty Cardinal when
she gave her praise report for Brother
Juan she mentioned that there were some
Satan possessed enemies that are
tormenting her and Lord God we just pray
for sister Patty you give her peace as
well Lord God you said that when a man
or woman's ways please the Lord he
maketh even their enemies to be at peace
and so I pray you keep Patty's mind
stayed on you Lord God that she would uh
continue to have the joy of the Lord and
continue to have a madeup mind that
she's going to walk with you and and
talk with you and serve you Faithfully
no matter what's going on until you
bring her through this season in her
life and God we come against those
powers of Darkness that are coming
against her Lord God anything that's
keeping her from seeing your plan in her
life clearly Lord God help her to see it
and find peace and give you the glory
Lord we also pray for your people today
you lay this on my heart that we would
Adorn the doctrine as you as you said in
the book of Titus Adorn the doctrine of
God cosmeo put it a beautify it make it
beautiful give us the wisdom Lord to
deliver this Everlasting gospel and even
the right hand of the Everlasting gospel
which is the health message help us to
deliver it in a way that is attractive
and alluring and and and that makes
people want to do better and to be
better and want to have some of what we
got in Jesus name help us not to be um
um arrogant help us not to be ugly help
us not to be um seeming self-righteous
and aloof Lord and and and just out of
touch with folks but help us to have a
connection that when the people see us
and when they hear us Lord God they know
that we have an absolute pure love for
them Hallelujah in jesus' name and that
we have something that is good God
because if if if if we all stuck up and
looking all grumpy and mean and proud
and nobody wants that what's attractive
about that and so let us show people
Jesus Lord hallelujah I pray that for
your church that we would Adorn the
doctrine of God thank you for Taj Lord
God those pulling currents that are and
revelation of Hope thank you for Tod's
beautiful videos and beautiful messages
Lord continue to bless him to bring
these inspiring and hopeful reflections
of hope uh through that incredible
Ministry that you've given him and I
just pray Lord God that each of us
because we know we feel it even in our
lower Fallen Natures we feel it the end
of me is always trying to pull me into
some old negative current and I just
pray God that your people under the
inspiration and power of the Holy Ghost
would just keep right on King that we
keep on pressing forward toward the mark
for the prize of the High Calling of God
in Christ Christ Jesus because you have
worked a miracle in our lives and you
put enmity between us and the evil one
if you have not worked that miraculous
miracle in our lives of putting enmity
between us and the serpent then we would
always be in League with fallen angels
and the devil and the world but now
you've given us hope and given us
strength and given us power may we keep
on pressing the battle to the gate in
Jesus name and not give into these
currents and we thank you Father for
hearing our and answering all of our
prayers today in Jesus name and finally
I just want to pray for the comings and
goings the comings and goings we love it
when we see new people come into living
Manner and then sometimes we see people
go out of living manner may we no matter
whether they're coming or whether
they're going may we be faithful to do
your will may we always show the love of
Jesus the smile of Jesus the Heart of
Jesus God The Compassion of Jesus and
while people are here for highever long
they got to be here maybe they will take
some of this living Mana anointing some
of this living Mana love some of this
living man of power back to their
churches Lord God and infect them with
the love and the goodness of God and the
power of the Holy Ghost Hallelujah I
pray that those who are leaving living
manner leave here with a song on their
lips with a praise in their heart with
Revelation from the word of God because
you've definitely given us the living
manner here at this place in Jesus name
and so we thank you Father that the
comings and goings Lord God they will
come and come and get blessed if they go
they go with a blessing and we give you
all of the glory honor and praise and we
also want to pray about living manner
Global that's amazing that is straight
fire right there God and we just thank
you that you allowing us the gifts of
the Holy Ghost are right here we
speaking in tongues Lord that Arabic was
fire today and so we thank you for it in
Jesus name that everyone who hears the
Everlasting gospel in their native
tongue Lord God will be moved with the
same power and compassion and the same
conviction they were moved with on the
day of Pentecost when they all heard
these men praising God and speaking the
wonderful words of God in their native
language thank you so much in Jesus
glorious name and now as we prepare to
hear the word of God from your
manservant today Lord I pray our hearts
will be attented that our minds will be
alert that we'll be ready to receive
Lord God and apply it to our lives in
Jesus glorious name all God's people
declare amen
[Music]
I give myself
away I give myself
away so will can use me I give
myself
[Music]
away I give
myself away so you can use me here I
am here I
stand Lord my life is in your your
hands Lord I am
longing to
see your
[Applause]
desires
revealed in
me I give myself
away I give myself
away so you can use me I give myself
[Music]
away I give myself
away so you can use me take my
heart take my
life as a
living SA
[Music]
all my
dreams all my
PL Lord I place them in your
hands I give myself
away oh God I give myself
away so you can you Lo me God I Give
Myself
Away
wo I give myself
away so you can use
me my life is not my
own to you I
belong I give my myself I give myself to
you my life is not my
own to you I
belong I give myself I give myself to
you father I give it to you Lord my life
is not my
own to you I
belong I give myself I give myself to
you yeah
yeah my life is not my
own to you I belong oh I give myself I
give myself I give myself to you
Lord my life is not my
own to you I belong
I give myself I give myself to
you so here I am to
worship here I am to bow down here I am
to say that you're my
God you're all together
worthy all together
lovely you're all together
wonderful to
me here I am to
worship here I am to bow down here I am
to say that you're my
God you're all together
lovely all together word worthy you're
all together wonderful you're wonderful
you're wonderful you're wonderful God
you're
beautiful you're beautiful you are
excellent you're mighty you're holy
you're worthy you are my healer You Are
My Redeemer God you're
beautiful you're beautiful and I worship
yes I worship you I lift my hands and
worship you I Bow Down and Worship You
Lord you're
beautiful you're beautiful to
me I'll
never
know how much it cost to see my sin
upon that
cross I'll
never
know how much it
cost to see my
sins upon that
cross I'll never
know how much it cost to you
see my
sins upon that
cross no greater love than
this then a man would lay down his life
for a
friend
oh no greater love than this
that a man would lay down his life for a
[Music]
friend God I owe you my
life God I owe you my
life you died that I might
live I'm forever
grateful I'm forever grate
fful
oh I present my body as a Living
Sacrifice holy unto you
Lord holy unto you
[Music]
Lord so I Give Myself Away
I give myself
away so
you can use me and give myself
away I give
myself away so
you can use me
Use Me
Jesus Use Me
[Music]
Lord here I am God we're
open for you to pour out
[Music]
hallelu you are worthy
amen there is no one
greater
Hu
e e
[Music]
what out is this so late to rest on
Mer's La is
sleeping oh manels gep with that thumbs
deep watch sh
watch
[Applause]
[Music]
keeping so PR King him and golden Mar
comp King to
hold him the king of King
salvation brings let love and a
andr him
[Music]
oh praise praise a song on high this
mother sings H love all about joy joy
for Christ is born the B the son of
Mary
oh this is Christ the
Lord oh
this the Christ theone
happy Sabbath everyone
uh we are getting ready to get into the
word of God please put a one in the chat
if you are ready if you are prepared uh
we are continuing our series entitled
the nine Essentials for the time of
trouble and I pray that your hearts have
been prepared to receive this message
and so we're going to pray and ask for
the Spirit uh to be with
us as we open the word of God let us
pray Heavenly Father we ask at this time
Lord that you would bless this meal Lord
we have eaten today and we desire to eat
again so Lord bless us with living Mana
that our hearts may be full
and that we we may go
forth powered by Your Word in and your
spirit in Jesus name we pray amen
amen we have been uh going through this
series we have been going through the
series um the nine Essentials for the
time of
trouble and we are we have covered the
fruit of Love of joy Jo of peace and now
we are on to part four of this series
which is patience
longsuffering let's go to the screen and
you'll note with me we're going to begin
with Revelation chapter
7 beginning with verse one the Bible
says and after these things I saw four
Angels standing on the four corners of
the Earth holding the Four Winds of the
earth that the wind should not blow on
the Earth nor on the sea nor on any tree
and I saw another Angel ascending from
the East having the Seal of the Living
God and he cried with a loud voice to
the four angels to whom it was given to
hurt the earth and the Sea saying hurt
not the Earth neither the sea nor the
trees till we have sealed the Servants
of our God in their
foreheads the first thing that I want
you to pay attention to is the fact that
these angels are holding back the Four
Winds and I want to focus in on those
winds what do these
winds
symbolize again please notice with me in
the Book of Daniel chapter 7 in verse
two Daniel says
this says Daniel spake and said I saw in
my vision by night and behold the Four
Winds of the heaven strove upon on the
great sea Daniel is envisioned
here and he too like
John sees these Four Winds but he
describes these Four
Winds as
striving upon the
Earth we need to understand that from
this text we we see the key that winds
represent strife so go ahead and put
that in the chat for me please winds
represent Strife in Proverbs chap 30 and
verse 33 the Bible says here surely the
churning of milk bringeth forth butter
and the wings and the ringing of the
nose bringeth forth blood so the forcing
of Wrath bringeth forth Strife what I
want you to see here is that these winds
when they are let loose represents
Strife they represent the wrath of man
and so please note that this time of
trouble that we have been focusing on it
is symbolized by a time when everything
is going to be chaotic when there is
going to be strife and wrath please note
with me in Matthew chapter 10 verse
21 Jesus himself said this and brother
shall deliver up the brother to death
and father the child and children shall
rise rise up against their parents and
cause them to be put to death and you
shall be hated of all Nations or of all
men for my name's
sake but he that
endureth to the end shall be saved in
this verse we saw what that Strife is
going to be that Strife is going to be
people betraying one another people
hating one another but then the text
says that he that endures to the end put
a one in the chat if you would like to
be among those that endure well the
question is endure what endure what we
just saw in Matthew chapter 10 some of
the things that would be that that God's
people will have to endure at the end of
time but Galatians chapter 5 gives us an
even clearer description because the
Wrath Of Man Would symbolize the work of
man the wrath that is going to be let
loose at the end of time is the wrath of
man and the wrath of man is the same
thing as the works of man or the works
of the flesh note with me in Galatians
chapter 5 and verse 19 the Bible
says now the works of the flesh are
manifest which are these adultery
fornication uncleanness
lasciviousness idolatry witchcraft
hatred very ience
emulations wrath Strife seditions
heresies envyings murderers murders
drunkenness reings and such the like of
which I tell you before as I've also
told you in time past that they which do
such things shall not inherit the
kingdom of God these are the things that
are going to be rampant upon the Earth
in the time of trouble these are the
things that God's people will have to
end
door but note beloved note how the text
continues the text says in Galatians
5:22 but the fruit of the spirit is love
joy peace longsuffering gentleness
goodness Faith meekness Temperance
against such there is no law what this
demonstrates to
us is that in the time of trouble there
is going to be a massive
[Music]
blowing of the works of the
flesh but God's people will have the
fruit of the spirit love joy peace
longsuffering gentleness goodness Faith
meekness Temperance but today we are
focusing particularly upon
longsuffering and let me say
this if you do not have
longsuffering all the other other
aspects of the fruits of the spirit will
fail you I'm going to say it again of
all of the fruit of the spirit I will
say that
longsuffering may be the most crucial to
have they are all equally important but
if you do not have
longsuffering then nothing else matters
and I'll explain why as we move through
this sermon what is
longsuffering come back with me to the
Book of Exodus
34:5 there God is speaking the Bible
says and the Lord God descended in the
cloud and stood with him there that is
Moses and proclaimed the name of the
Lord and the Lord passed by before him
and proclaimed the Lord the Lord God
merciful and gracious longsuffering and
abundant in goodness and truth now I
want you to note here you'll remember
that that those who are sealed at the
end of time are sealed with the name of
God and when God actually declares his
name you will see that it is basically
the fruit of the spirit those who are
sealed at the end of time are sealed as
it were in the character or the name of
God they demonstrate the fruit of the
spirit what I want to focus on as God is
speaking his name one of the attributes
of God part of his name is
longsuffering so what does this word
longsuffering mean please note with me
on the
screen according to the Strong's
Concordance the word literally means
patient or
slow to
anger slow to anger now please
note we just saw that these winds that
are let loose at the End of Time
represent the Winds of strife The Winds
of anger a and winds are are designed to
to to pick up velocity if you will so
that when the winds blow it becomes
easier and quick if you go with the wind
if you go with the flow it will it will
it will it will speed up your process of
strife and anger it will get you to from
zero to 10 in a
second but the spirit or the gift or the
fruit of
longsuffering is
specifically being
slow to
anger slow to Wrath when the for winds
are let loose loose wrath wrath wrath
wrath designed to carry you away Robin
wrath blowing
everywhere which means that Satan will
attempt to test your
longsuffering are you really slow to
anger this is why the Bible tells us in
Revelation chapter 14:12 here is the
patience of the Saints here are they
that keep the Commandments of God and
have the faith of Jesus it is the
patience of the saints that are going to
be that's going to be
tested and beloved if you don't have
patience if you're not slow to anger it
will lead to Breaking the Commandments
of God and denying the faith of Jesus
and this is why I say again that that
endurance or patience may be the most
critical fruit of the spirit
come back with me to James
1:12 in James 1:12 the Bible says
blessed is the man that
endureth
Temptation for when he is tried he shall
receive the Crown of Life which the Lord
has promised to them that love him
please note here that it is not those
who who face
temptation but those who endure temp
Temptation if the letting loose of the
Four Winds represents God's people being
tried and God's people being tried by
Temptation then we also see here that
endurance or patience is the key thing
that is going to allow God's people to
get
through this time of
trouble now
again you may ask the question endure in
what
come on let's go back to the
screen let's go back to the
screen the Bible says this this I say
then walk in the spirit and you shall
not fulfill the lust of the flesh for
the flesh lusteth against the spirit and
the spirit against the Flesh and these
are contrary to one to the other so that
you cannot do the things that you would
the Bible says if we walk in the spirit
you shall not fulfill the lust of the
flesh y'all put Amen in the chat if
you're following if you walk in the
spirit you shall not fulfill the lust of
the flesh so the question
is what does it mean to walk in the
spirit please note that it didn't say if
you sprint in the
spirit it said if you walk in the spirit
walking in the spirit denotes something
that is longterm
walking in the spirit requires something
let me ask you a question what does
walking in the spirit require give me a
word what is the word I'm looking for to
walk not on and off but continually in
the spirit
requires
endurance put the word in the chat for
me
please to walk continually in the spirit
requires
endurance in other words God is trying
to teach us how to
endure in the
spirit not how to jump in and out of the
Spirit In the Flesh in the spirit in the
flesh in the spirit he's trying to teach
us how to endure in the spirit and so
what I want you to understand understand
beloved is that it is not those who Jump
In the Flesh and then jump in the spirit
and then jump In the Flesh and then jump
in the spirit no no no you're pray
you're playing Russian
roulette God is looking to produce in us
a perseverance in the spirit an
endurance in the spirit a patience in
the spirit he's trying to teach us how
to
continually be slow to wrath James
chapter 1 19 the Bible tells us in James
119 wherefore my beloved Brethren let
every man be swift to hear slow to speak
slow to wrath for the wrath of man
worketh not the righteousness of God is
another way of saying the wrath of man
Works
unrighteousness God is trying to teach
us how how to walk
continually in righteousness how to walk
continually in rightdoing notice what
the Bible says here in Hebrews the book
of Hebrews 12:2 the Bible says looking
onto Jesus the author and finisher of
our faith who for the joy that was set
before him what did he
do what did he do he endured the cross
do y'all catch that for the
joy we've talked about that already the
joy for the joy that was set before him
he endured the cross God is calling us
to the same he's calling us to learn how
to endure now let me break this down for
you endure in
what endure in the
spirit endure in the Fruit of the Spirit
that means that I love not just when
things are good but also when things are
bad I have joy not just when things are
good but also when things are bad I have
peace not just when things are good but
also when things are bad this is why I
said beloved that endurance that that
that uh longsuffering may be the most
important or the most crucial element of
the Fruit of the Spirit because you can
love
sometimes all of us love sometimes we
all have joy sometimes we all experience
peace sometimes we all can be gentle
sometimes we all can exercise goodness
sometimes we all can exercise Faith
meekness and Temperance sometimes but
beloved God is Not Looking for sometimes
Christians he's looking for Christians
who will be able to endure in love end
endure in Joy endure in peace endure in
in gentleness endure in goodness endure
in faith whether things are good or not
he's looking for people who who who are
able to
endure
persevere patiently
exercise patiently live out what God has
asked them to do
and we see Jesus beloved doing this on
the cross he
endured such a heavy weight upon his
shoulders on our behalf and beloved that
was an example of what God's people will
be required to do in the time of trouble
which is why beloved we are talking
about this fruit today the fruit of
longsuffering it is the ability to
endure the best example one of the best
examples we can see from this is when
Jesus himself according to the Book of
Matthew
4:1 the Bible says here then was Jesus
led up of the spirit Into the Wilderness
to be tempted of the devil and when he
had fasted 40 days and 40 nights he was
afterward hungry listen beloved I need
y'all to understand something that for
those 40 days and 40 nights Jesus
endured he endured in the fruit of the
spirit that means that while he was in
the wilderness he endured in love he
endured in Joy he endured in peace he
endured in the fruit of the spirit for
40 days and 40 nights beloved walking in
the
spirit what an example Lord you're
calling me to not be fickle with my love
with my joy with my peace your you're
calling me to learn how to walk in these
things
continually listen to the
statement letter 218 July 16th 1908
speaking of Jesus in the wilderness
here's what elen white says the strength
of the temptation to indulge perverted
appetite can be measured only by the
long suffering of Christ in his long
fast in the wilderness do you see how
she used the word longsuffering in
connection with Christ being in the
wilderness beloved I need y'all to
understand this that God is calling us
to endure he's calling
us to persevere he's calling us to be
slow to anger listen to what Psalms
Proverbs 16:32 says he that is slow to
anger is better than the mighty he that
ruleth his Spirit than he that taketh a
city
beloved Jesus calls
us to rule ourselves to be slow to anger
to conquer our own Spirit again Proverbs
15 ver 18 a wrathful man stirreth up
Strife but he that is slow to anger
appeaseth appeaseth Strife I need you to
understand beloved that the test at the
end of time is going to be Satan
literally seeking to get you caught up
in the spirit of strife in the spirit of
anger in the spirit of Wrath in fact
when they tried to kill Jesus I love how
the Bible puts this in Luke Chapter 6:1
the Bible says and they were all filled
with Madness and communed one with
another what they might do to Jesus it's
almost as if the Bible is is calling
Madness a spirit they were all filled
with Madness and communed what they
might do to Jesus I need you to
understand that when these four winds
are let loose let's read it again
revelation 7:1 after these things I saw
four Angels standing on the four corners
of the Earth holding the Four Winds of
the earth that they should not that the
wind should not blow on the earth nor on
the sea nor on any tree and I saw
another Angel ascending from the East
having the Seal of the Living God and he
cried with a loud voice to the four
angels to whom it was given to hurt the
earth and the sea
hurt the earth and the Sea saying hurt
not the Earth neither the sea nor the
trees till we have sealed the Servants
of our God in their forehead what I need
you to understand is that when these
winds are let loose The Strife the wrath
of man will be at an alltime High the
world will have never seen or witnessed
such Strife upon the planet and unless
you are rooted and grounded in the Holy
Spirit you will be blown away by the
winds of strife unless beloved you are
consistent in love and consistent in joy
and consistent in peace if you are up
and down in these things beloved it is
time to ask the Holy Spirit to truly
come in and Grant GI you know what I was
able to walk in love for like 20 minutes
today Lord tomorrow help me to walk in
love for 40 minutes help me to walk in
love for 6 hours help me to walk in love
for the entire day yes Lord I walked in
love for the entire day help me to get
to two days help me to get to four days
help me to walk in this thing
consistently help me to stop being so
blown over by the Winds of
strife listen to what James chapter 1:3
says James chapter 1:3 knowing this that
the trying of your faith worketh
patience but let patience have her
perfect work that you may be perfect and
entire wanting nothing God is calling us
beloved to have
patience
longsuffering listen to
this in the Book of Revelation chapter
14:8 the Bible says there followed
another Angel saying Babylon is Fallen
is Fallen that great City because she
made all nations drink of the wine of
the what the wine of the wrath of her
fornication it goes on to say in verse 9
or verse 10 that the same shall drink of
the wine of the wrath of God which is
poured out without mixture into the cup
of his indignation those who exercise
human wrath will experience Divine wrath
those who exercise human wrath who are
swallowed up with human wrath in that
time will experience the wrath of God
but notice what we're told we're told in
the book of Psalm 37 Psalm 37 the Bible
says this fret not thyself because of
evildoers neither be thou envious
against the workers of iniquity for they
shall soon be cut down like the grass
and wither as the green herb trust in
the Lord and do good so shalt thou dwell
in the land verily that thou shalt be
fed Delight thyself also in the Lord and
He Shall give Thee the desires of thine
heart commit thy way unto the Lord trust
also in him and he shall bring it to
pass and he shall bring forth thy
righteousness as the light and thy
judgment as the noon day watch
this rest in the Lord and wait patiently
for him fret not thyself because of him
who prospered in his way because of the
man who bringeth wickedness Wicked
devices to pass cease from anger and
forsake wrath threet not thyself in any
wise to do evil for evildoers shall be
cut off but those that wait upon the
Lord they shall inherit the earth I want
y'all to understand this
imagine with me the time of
trouble that people are going to be
doing things and saying
things that will be will be
designed to get you stirred up with the
spirit of
Wrath
wrath in in trying to protect those that
you love Wrath
in so many different ways the devil is
going to say can I get you to
snap can I get you to
respond in Anger can I get you to be
just like the people that are
persecuting you can I provoke you yes
Michelle can I provoke you to become so
angry with those who are doing
evil can I provoke you to
hate those who are doing it can I
provoke you to have wrath towards those
who don't see things the way that you do
can I provoke you to be angry with the
Heathen can I provoke you to be angry
and wrathful to your
persecutors do y'all remember the story
of
Jonah when God sends Jonah to go
preached to that Wicked and rebellious
City a and the Bible tells us that Jonah
went to preach and then God forgave the
city because they repented and y'all
remember what Jonah
did what did Jonah do let's go to the
screen Jonah chapter 4 vers1 the Bible
says but it it displeased
Jonah
exceedingly and he was very angry watch
this
and he prayed unto and he prayed unto
the Lord and said I pray thee Oh Lord
was not this my saying when I was yet in
my country therefore I fled before unto
tarus for I knew that thou art gracious
a gracious God and
merciful
slow I don't like that you're slow to
anger I want you to destroy my enemies I
want you to
destroy the
Heathen you know I I've had people ask
me or say to me you know Pastor uh
you're unbalanced because you're not
preaching against what the Heathen are
doing and this is what I always
respond I always respond
listen the Heathen aren't even tuning in
to
church the reason the Heathen aren't
tuning tuning into the
church is because the church is so full
of
hypocrisy and yet they're pointing at
the beam in the heathen's
eye why are you always pointing at the
beam in the CH in in in in in the eyes
of those who profess Christianity who
profess the
truth you see beloved our spirit that
Spirit of condemn the Heathen tell the
Heathen that they're wrong
is it possible that the devil can be
putting in you the spirit of Wrath under
a disguise of the spirit of
righteousness oh man I so righteous I
hate to see what the Heathen are doing
to our country to our nation I hate
those
Heathen really is that who Jesus is
that's not the name of GE that's not the
name of God in the forehead that's
somebody else's Spirit that's somebody
else's
name and this is exactly what the devil
is going to amplify at the end of
time get mad at your persecutors hate
your
persecutors the Bible says of job James
5:1 James 5:1 the Bible says behold we
count them happy that endure you have
heard of the patience of Job and have
seen the end of the Lord that the Lord
is very pitiful and tender Mercy job
endured yall remember what job did at
the end of The Book of Job he prayed for
those people that were speaking against
him he prayed for those people that were
speaking against
him please understand beloved this is
why the Bible tells us in Luke 21 21: 19
in your patience possess ye your souls
do you see that if you have
patience if you have patience with other
people patience with those who don't
understand as you do patience with your
own walk endurance in your own walk in
your patience possess you your souls so
the devil knows if he can get you to not
endure you're going to be
lost that's why the Bible says he that
endures to the end the same shall be
saved but do not get it wrong beloved it
is not your patience come with me to the
screen John The Book of Revelation chap
1 ver9 I John who am also your brother
and companion in Tribulation and in the
kingdom and patience of Jesus Christ
whoa so you mean it's not your patience
no it's not your patience it is the
patience of Jesus Christ in fact in
Romans chapter 15:5 the Bible literally
calls God the god of patience if you
lack patience go to the god of patience
if you lack patience ask for the
patience of Jesus Christ beloved this is
the only thing that will allow us to
endure and this is why we need the
spirit this is why we need the Holy
Spirit dwelling in
us and beloved this brings me to a very
important
point in the Book of John 20 verse 21
and 22 the Bible says this then said
Jesus to them peace be unto you as my
father has sent me even so I send you
and then he said this he and when he had
said this he breathed upon them and said
unto them receive ye the Holy Ghost
let's pause for a second let's pause for
a
second so Jesus breathes on his
disciples and says receive the Holy
Ghost in breathing upon his
disciples he was signifying this is the
spirit the spirit is like the Breath of
Life the spirit is your if you want to
live you got to breathe the spirit you
got to breathe the
spirit so if Jesus gives us the spirit
it it's almost as if that Spirit becomes
our our spiritual Breath of Life and as
I say what I'm about to say it might
sound strange to you at first but you'll
catch
it only those who can exercise breath
control y'all put a five in the chat if
you understood what I just said only
those who are able to exercise breath
control deep breathing deep breathing
not shallow
breathing deep
breathing when the winds are let
loose it's as if we're going to need to
know how to hold our
breath let me say it
again it's as if we are going to need to
know how to hold hold hold on
to our breath our
life the spirit of God in
us we're going to need to know how to
hold our breath how long can you you
ever try to hold your breath test I
don't know how long you can hold your
breath but we're not talking about that
kind of hold your breath here we're not
talking about the kind of hold of your
breath where you're not breathing we're
talking about the kind of hold your
breath where you hold on to the spirit
and don't let go because the devil's
going to test how long can you hold that
breath how long can you hold the breath
of Jesus in you how long can you hold on
to that Spirit I'm going to try to get
you to grieve the spirit I'm going to
try to get you to let go of the spirit
I'm going to try to let get you to
Exhale the spirit I'm going to test to
see how long you can actually hold your
spirit and unless we learn beloved how
to exercise breath control except we
learn how to hold our breath so that as
we're holding the breath we're all we're
actually breathing in the spirit we're
learning how to hold the spirit so that
we do not let go of the spirit beloved
in that time of trouble when the winds
are let loose God's people are going to
have to hold their
breath God's people are going to have to
hold their breath how long we're not
told we're not told but guess
what you're going to have to hold your
breath cuz the devil's going to try to
make it so that you are out of breath
and if you're out of breath everything
else
fails if you are out of breath
everything else fails so beloved watch
this you might be able to Sprint joy and
Sprint love and Sprint peace and Sprint
gentleness and Sprint goodness a you
know what oh it's not that far yeah let
me just let me just Sprint some love
real quick and you can Sprint and come
back H I get my break no but but this
we're not asked
to to Sprint with
patience did y'all catch up just now
we're not asked to Sprint the race we're
asked to run the race with
patience so now when I've got to run in
a in a way that requires me to
endure yeah you're you're you're a
you're a good love Sprinter but can you
endure in love
you're a good Joy Sprinter oh I'm joyous
right now but can you endure in
Joy can you endure the the the the
challenge at the End of Time beloved is
not whether you can exercise bouts of
Love bouts of Joy but can
you go the
distance that's the
test can you run the
distance in the Fruit of the Spirit
please understand this is why God is
holding those winds back because he's
ultimately trying to seal us with his
character that's why the name of the
Lord is essentially the very description
of the fruit of the
spirit
longsuffering
merciful
goodness beloved
listen listen I need y'all to catches
note with me in Genesis 2:7 you'll
remember the Bible says there the Lord
God formed Man Out of the Dust of the of
the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life and Man
became a living Soul right so so the
spirit is is a symbol or a type of the
breath or the life of man watch
this in the beginning of the world
wind was blown upon the Earth the Bible
says in Genesis chapter 1 verse one in
the beginning God created the Heaven and
the Earth and the Earth was was without
form and void and darkness was upon the
face of the deep and the spirit of God
the ruach of God the wind of God moved
upon the face of the waters and we
understand that according to John 3:8
the wind is symbolic of the spirit the
wind bloweth where it listeth and thou
hearest the sound thereof but cannot
tell whence it cometh and whether it
goeth so is everyone that is born of the
spirit why am I sharing this because
beloved when Revelation chapter 7 speaks
about these four winds that are being
let loose beloved I need y'all to
understand that this is Strife that is
brought on by another
spirit it's going to be in the
air and unless you know how to hold your
breath unless you know how to hold your
breath you will will be
infected by that demonic Spirit you will
be infected by that Wicked Spirit you
will be infected by that evil spirit and
so this time of trouble is a time where
God's people are going to have to know
how to hold your breath How To Go the
Distance how to to to last and Outlast
the
flesh how to Outlast the attacks of the
enemy this is why the Bible says endure
hardship as a good soldier of Jesus
Christ
endure note with me Matthew chapter 18
Matthew 18 we are almost done just a
just a few more verses we got this this
Parable we're going to hit a few more
verses I need y'all to catch this Jesus
saith unto him remember that the
question was asked how often shall my
enemy sin against me and I forgive him
till seven times and Jesus said unto him
I said say not unto the until seven
times but until 70 time
7 I want y'all to
know that your your you will be tested
upon this 70 Time s principle in the
time of trouble your 70 time 7 will be
tested will will be
tested really forgive your enemy how
many times all right well I'mma send 70
* 7 towards you right now let's see see
let's see if you can forgive your
enemy
twice let's see if you can forgive your
enemy even
twice just like
job Lord I I guarantee you if you let me
at them I will demonstrate that they
don't really love you I will demonstrate
that they're not really fed of the
spirit I will demonstrate that they will
disres that they will that they will
drag your name through the mud I will
demonstrate
H come on let's go back to the parable
the Bible says
here therefore the Kingdom of Heaven is
like unto a certain King which would
take account of his servants and when he
had begun to reckon one was brought unto
him which owed him 10,000 talents but
for as much as he had not to pay the
Lord com his Lord commanded him to be
sold and his wife and his children and
all that he had and payment to be made
the servant therefore fell down and
worshiped him saying Lord have what p
patience with me and I will pay thee all
Lord please be longsuffering with me
then the Lord of that servant was moved
with
compassion wow so
compassion patience
longsuffering oh that's all that that
it's all the same thing it's all the
same thing so he loosed them and forgave
him the debt Oh you mean longsuffering
slow to wrath means also being willing
to
forgive hm
but the same servant went out and found
one of his fellow servants which owed
him 100 p and he laid hold on him and
took him by the throat saying pay me
what you owe me and his fellow servant
fell down at his feet and besought him
saying have patience with me and I will
pay thee all and he would not but he
went and cast him into prison till he
should pay the debt so when his fellow
servants saw what was done they were
very sorry and came and told unto their
lord all that was done
and then they bring him to the let me go
back so he comes before his his master
and he says this should not thou have
had compassion on thy fellow servant
even as I had pity on thee compassion
pity
longsuffering you guys is all tied in
and his Lord was wroth and delivered him
to the tormenters till he should pay all
that was due unto him so likewise shall
my heavenly father do also unto you if
you from your hearts forgive not every
forgive not your brother his
transgressions you know what this is why
I beloved as we look at the example of
Jesus when he said father forgive them
for they know not what they
do father forgive them for they know not
what they
do as we look at the example of Jesus
beloved we s we see someone who did not
let go of the spirit he never let go of
the spirit from his birth to his death
Jesus held his
breath Jesus held his breath never let
it
go when his enemies came against him
father forgive them for they know not
what they
do so many of us don't know how to pray
that prayer so many of us don't
understand what it means to be
longsuffering what it means to be
forgiven what it means to pray for your
enemies
no so many of us are in a place where we
rejoice when we see our enemies
something happen to our enemies we
Rejoice over the misgivings of our or
the mishap happen happenings of our of
our
enemy we want those who are against our
heavenly
father to to face the wrath of God and
we're going to rejoice and pull out the
popcorn when we when we see that that
happened beloved this is the spirit of
the
enemy this is the spirit of strife this
is the spirit of
Wrath again let me read to you in
closing Hebrews chapter 12 and verse one
our closing text the text says wherefore
seeing we also are compassed about with
so great a cloud of witnesses let us lay
aside every weight and the sin which
does so easily beset us and let us
run with
patience not
Sprint run with patience the race that
is set before
us beloved today you have
learned that it is not enough to have
love joy peace longsuffering gentleness
goodness Faith meekness Temperance it is
not enough to possess these things when
things are
convenient we have learned today that
longsuffering is that is that
underlying
principle that allows us to endure in
love to endure in joy to endure in peace
to even endure in longsuffering and this
is why if we don't have longsuffering
our love
is simply temporary our joy is simply
temp temporary and all the devil has to
do is bring something our way love is
gone out the window Joy is out the
window and especially in the time of
trouble you could forget
it and so today you've come to the
understanding Lord I need
consistency in the fruit of the spirit
Lord grant me longsuffering so I can
consistently forgive 70 time 7 so that I
can consistent love so I can
consistently have joy consistently have
peace Lord teach me to be longsuffering
teach me to endure teach me to endure
teach me to endure if that is your
desire I'm going to ask you to put that
four in the chat because we are on part
four of the series we've got five more
to go but right now I put that four in
the chat because you're saying Lord
teach me to endure I want to be able to
endure I want to be able to to to endure
in love joy peace longsuffering gentl
goodness Faith meekness Temperance let
me not be up and down wishy-washy in
this teach me to endure the number four
to rhyme with endure Lord teach me how
to endure teach me how to endure
heavenly father I thank you for speaking
to us today Lord for showing us that
without endurance our love is fickle our
joy is fickle Lord without endurance
without
longsuffering we cannot endure any trial
we cannot endure the things that we face
you've called us to endure hardness as a
good soldier of Jesus Christ teach us
Lord to have the spirit of
endurance Lord may we fulfill the
patience of the
Saints by having the patience of Jesus
Christ received from the god of
patience that your name
which includes patience will be written
Upon Our
foreheads thank you Lord for hearing and
answering our prayer because we ask it
in the precious and holy name of Jesus
let everyone say amen and amen may God
bless you as you continue to follow the
lord um I do want to want to uh share
that if there's anyone watching today
who would like to enroll in Bible study
for the purpose of baptism please reach
out to our Bible worker I think we'll be
able to put the um the uh the uh email
address uh up either in the link or on
the screen we're also going to put a
link in the chat for the uh Afterglow if
you'd like to join us and discuss what
you learned during Sabbath school or
what you ate during Sabbath school and
what you ate for the Divine service we
welcome you to come on and fellowship
with us and again may God bless you as
uh you continue your walk in the Lord
may this series this nine part series
really help you tremendously if you've
missed part one two or three go back
they're all up online for you to watch
so that you can catch up and be ready
for parts five six 7 eight and nine may
God bless you and keep you we'll put the
link in the chat and uh again may God
bless you and keep you link for the
Afterglow and uh by the way if you want
the sermons um the notes for these
sermons we're going to put this uh last
slide up on the screen and you can
connect with LM you can uh send in your
prayer requests uh you can follow me on
social media and there is our Bible
worker uh contact information uh but
let's go ahead and put that link for
alra live up in the uh in the chat and
may God bless you and keep you
thank you for joining us today if this
is your first time worshiping with us
please check out our website at Living
mana. Church we are not just here for
Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical Health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]